<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-12-02T16:16:20+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Jinning&apos;s personal website. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Laws of Emotional Mastery</title><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/laws-of-emotional-mastery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Laws of Emotional Mastery"/><published>2024-10-15T15:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-15T15:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/laws-of-emotional-mastery</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/laws-of-emotional-mastery/"><![CDATA[<p>By Noam Shpancer Ph.D. | Published May 4, 2021 | Last reviewed on August 16, 2022</p> <p>Life, goes the saying, is like a diamond—hard and beautiful. Many are experiencing the hardness of it quite acutely these days, in the form of stress, dread, and fatigue. Much of our success in navigating these difficult times depends on our mental health.</p> <p>People may visualize mental health as a place one arrives at or a treasure one possesses. But mental health is neither a destination nor a property. Rather, it is something you do—the practice of proper mind management.</p> <p>Your mind is a lot like a car: Both churn with energy; both can take you places; both can veer off course to devastating effect. Most important, the usefulness of both will depend in large part on how you handle them.</p> <p>Good driving is a process of constant adaptation characterized by high responsivity and requiring myriad specific skills: how to take a turn, merge into traffic, change lanes safely. Likewise, sound mental health is a process of constant adaptation, characterized by psychological flexibility—the ability to recognize and adjust your mindset and behavior to various situations so as not to callously hurt yourself or others, and so that you may continue to represent your values and pursue worthy goals in the face of distractions and obstacles.</p> <p>Like driving, the process of mental health requires its own set of specific skills. Here, the skills in question are those that let us manage well the products of the mind—our thoughts, emotions, and behavior. Psychological science provides some useful instructions for that purpose.</p> <h2 id="think-accurately">Think Accurately.</h2> <p>Lying in bed at night, you hear a sudden “thud” coming from downstairs. What do you feel? What do you do? Your subsequent emotion and action will depend on what you tell yourself—your interpretation of what the noise means. If you think, This is just snow falling from the roof, you’ll likely turn back to sleep unbothered. But thinking, A burglar is at my window, will get your heart racing and have you reaching for your phone or gun, depending on your politics.</p> <p>Cognitive psychology research over the past few decades has shown that our thoughts—beliefs and subjective interpretations—give rise to our emotions and behavior. Thinking, in other words, is important for our emotional state.</p> <p>One oft-repeated axiom of advice is that you should, therefore, strive to “think positively.” Positive thinking gets good press, and in proper doses it can be useful. Optimism, as the work of psychologist Martin Seligman and others has shown, can help us endure periods of hardship, bolster a sense of hope, and improve mood.</p> <p>Alas, positivity, while differing in content, is similar in process to negativity: Both are biases, and both obscure and distort the truth. Basing a response on anything other than the truth carries grave risks. If you’re falling, there’s no use in telling yourself that you’ve learned how to fly. Decisions guided by truth and facts are more likely to prove successful. Sound mental health is served best by accurate thinking.</p> <p>Thoughts are like viruses. Letting the wrong one into your system may cause harm. Bad thoughts—racism is one—have caused more damage than bad viruses. And they’re harder to eradicate.</p> <p>Accurate thinking amounts to an informal application of the scientific method—a process of refereeing between competing truth claims based on evidence. To develop accurate thinking skills, we must first appreciate that our brain’s operations rely on two central processes: control and automatic. Control processes are slow, effortful, and highly vulnerable to disruption; they demand concentration and full attention. Automatic processes are fast, robust against disruption, and do not require attention or concentration in order to operate successfully.</p> <p>Learning how to drive a car is a control process— effortful and demanding. But 10 years later, your driving has shifted to automatic—effortless and requiring no concentration. Such autonomous operations have an important evolutionary role: They free up energy and allow conscious attention, a limited resource, to focus on what is new. That permits us to keep up with the ever dynamic conditions of reality, the better to survive and thrive.</p> <p>Habits are automatic processes operating outside of awareness. This fact has two main implications. First, you cannot describe something well if you aren’t aware of it. The more automatic a process becomes, the less information is available to us about how it works—one reason great players are not often great coaches. Their playing, what they do over and over, has become automatized; they no longer have clear conscious knowledge of how they do it. Second, you cannot change what you’re not aware of. A habit in motion tends to stay in motion.</p> <p>Throughout our life we acquire “thought habits”—automatic ways of thinking about the world and ourselves. Functional thought habits—like good eating, sleeping, or driving habits—help us operate efficiently and safely. However, distorted thought habits—like poor eating, sleeping, or driving habits—will over time result in psychological pain and maladjustment.</p> <p>If, for example, you’ve developed a thought habit of believing that anything short of perfection is failure, then you are bound to judge yourself a failure often, thus experiencing psychic pain. Your actual problem is not imperfection—which is merely a condition of all humanity, excepting Beyoncé—but the distorted automatic belief that perfection is the only form of success.</p> <p>Distorted thinking habits are not usually adopted randomly or through some mind abnormality, but because they served a useful purpose at the time of their adoption. For example, after years of driving to your place of employment, you need not notice the road. The route has been automatized, allowing your thoughts to wander quite freely during your commute. It’s a fine, adaptive habit.</p> <p>But if your office is suddenly moved to a new location across town, the same old habit is rendered maladaptive. You’ll need to exert effort, pay attention, and use your control processes to learn a new route.</p> <p>Sound mind maintenance likewise requires identification and change of outdated and ineffective thinking habits. Doing this takes several steps. First, you need to become aware of your thinking habits. In other words, you need to think about your thinking in order to detect recurring patterns. You can do this by asking yourself such questions as, What am I telling myself right now? or What thoughts come up for me in these kinds of situations?</p> <p>The second step is to realize that your initial thoughts in a given situation are just old habits at work rather than truth revealed. Thoughts in general are not world events but mind events. They are not facts but hypotheses, conjectures about what may or may not be. As such, you can observe them dispassionately and with curiosity and choose whether to engage or let them drift by like clouds in the sky. Such detached awareness may sometimes in itself neutralize the corrosive effects of troubling thoughts.</p> <p>Becoming aware of a distorted thinking habit also allows you to change it. Awareness alone, however, is insufficient: Realizing a place exists doesn’t automatically get you there. You need not know why a habit arose, but to replace it you’ll need to challenge and engage actively with the old thought habit.</p> <p>To do so, you’ll want to first generate several alternative thoughts. Ask yourself, What else may be going on? What else may happen? What else can I tell myself here? Then, evaluate the different thoughts based on evidence. (Asking yourself, Which of these thoughts would I bet my life on, if I had to? may encourage your evidence search.) Finally, choose the thought that is supported by the best evidence. Then repeat that thought to yourself and act from it.</p> <p>Accurate thinking is like buying eyewear. You don’t just grab onto the first pair of glasses you see. Rather, you check out the merchandize, try on a few pairs, pick several viable candidates for purchase, compare them based on assorted criteria of evidence— fit, price, style, brand—and choose the most appropriate pair for you. As with your glasses so with your thoughts. It’s best to inspect and evaluate the merchandize before making a purchase.</p> <h2 id="neither-deny-nor-obey-emotionsaccept-them">Neither Deny nor Obey Emotions—Accept Them.</h2> <p>Emotions hold great sway over our lives, coloring and flavoring experience. That said, it is useful to remember that emotions, like thoughts, are mind events not world events, which means that we have much say in regulating them.</p> <p>Science has yet to fully decipher the nature, structure, and origins of emotional experience. What we do know is that, pragmatically, emotions constitute a type of data that is often useful for navigating the world. A measure of emotional arousal helps us learn new things and remember important events. A baby’s cry of distress effectively summons the caregiver’s attention. Fear keeps you off the dangerous edge of the cliff.</p> <p>However, as with data in general, two questions loom large over emotional experience: First, are the data any good, or are they incomplete, corrupt, or distorted in some important way? And second, what’s the best response, given the data?</p> <p>Psychological research from David Barlow and others has shown that mental distress often emerges not from emotional experience itself but from errors in emotion regulation—mistakes in handling the data. The first such common error is that of denial, whereby emotions are resisted, disallowed, or avoided. This happens when you tell yourself you’re not allowed to feel what you’re feeling. Feeling the jitters before a big presentation, you admonish yourself to not get anxious.</p> <p>The impulse to deny emotions, particularly negative ones, is understandable. Negative emotions are no fun, and we often associate them with negative events and outcomes that we wish to avoid or forget. In fact, research from George Vaillant and others has shown that a measure of conscious emotion suppression—choosing not to engage or talk about distressing feelings—is often a useful, healthy coping mechanism. Such suppression, however, entails awareness, acceptance, and a lack of fear in the face of the emotion.</p> <p>Denial, on the other hand, denotes a fearful unwillingness to feel. Attempts at denial are ineffective, for several reasons. First, one law of our internal architecture is that whatever you tell yourself you’re not allowed to feel or think, you’re already feeling and thinking. Pushing against emotion is thus futile, as ill-advised and as fatiguing as swimming against a riptide.</p> <p>Moreover, designating a certain emotion as forbidden, intolerable, or dangerous can make you hypervigilant about the very emotion you’re trying to deny. Constant vigilance about an impending negative experience becomes a negative experience in itself.</p> <p>Finally, habits of denying negative emotions may, over time, morph into “experiential avoidance,” a general tendency to avoid difficult internal experiences. Research from Steven Hayes and others has identified experiential avoidance as an underlying factor in much psychopathology, for several reasons.</p> <p>Life is an obstacle course even in the best of times. Keeping one’s bearings and achieving meaningful goals involve a willingness to face and overcome adversity. If your only response to difficulty is to back off, you’ll end up retreating from life itself. Inability to tolerate difficult emotion impoverishes your mental life.</p> <p>Avoidance is appealing because it brings quick relief. The human brain is biased toward favoring short-term calculations and immediate gratifications. Rewards that are placed within our reach loom larger than faraway consequences. The bucket of fat-drenched French fries is all the more enticing for being right here in front of me, while the looming heart attack is years in the future, dimly sketched in the mind. No wonder I reach for the fries.</p> <p>Life was once—in our species’ early environs—precarious, strictly a short-term proposition. Privileging immediate reward was adaptive. Our lives now are, with any luck, long term and require long-term strategies. Holding your breath works to keep you alive under water in the short term; it is not effective for long-term submersion. Likewise the habit of avoidance, effective in the short term, becomes maladaptive over time.</p> <p>Avoidance teaches you nothing but how to evade more, and therefore tends to metastasize with time. The more you avoid, the less competent, knowledgeable, and confident you become, and the less of life you can fully experience.</p> <p>The second common mistake in handling emotions may be called “emotional obedience.” We assume our emotions represent the truth, the whole truth, and nothing but the truth and must therefore drive our actions: I’m scared, therefore I must run. I’m angry, therefore I must fight.</p> <p>Such emotionally driven behaviors are problematic because research has shown—and self-reflection will no doubt confirm—that our emotions often provide distorted, partial, and biased information. A roller coaster ride may produce genuine terror, but it presents no real danger, short of badly messed up hair. Things we fear more (airplanes, strangers) are often safer than things we fear less (cars, family members). Your drunken insistence that you feel fine to drive is another case in point.</p> <p>Even when they tell a true story, our emotions rarely capture the whole of it. How you feel about buying a house is important, but far from the only consideration in finding an abode. Budget, family size, neighborhood, market conditions, and available alternatives matter too, often more so.</p> <p>To properly regulate emotional data, we must refrain from either denying or obeying emotions. Instead, there’s a simple two-step process. The first step is acceptance. Emotions are, in a sense, internal weather, and it’s as advisable to accept the truth and fact of our emotions as we do the weather’s. If you’re anxious or sad, your best first move is to acknowledge and accept what you feel: I am human. Humans have emotions. This emotion is part of my experience right now.</p> <p>Acceptance confers benefits. It is a form of facing facts, like describing a difficult event in honest detail. Doing so may be hard, but it manifests your courage and builds your strength. In accepting your emotions, you are also accepting the truth of your situation—a base from which to fashion a successful response.</p> <p>Accepting emotion also negates the exhausting and futile effort involved in denial and affords you the opportunity to examine and get to know a part of your experience. Knowledge is power. Self-knowledge is self-empowering.</p> <p>Finally, accepting a negative emotion lessens its destructive potential. Caught in a riptide, your best move is not to resist but to let the current take you out to sea. Soon, the current will weaken and disperse, and you’ll be able to swim around it and back safely to shore.</p> <p>Acceptance does not imply blind emotional obedience. Rather, the next step in proper emotion management is to decide what to do with the emotion data. Once you acknowledge that it’s raining, it is still up to you to decide how to act vis-à-vis that fact.</p> <p>Emotions tend to be good consultants but lousy executives. We are well advised to consider their input but ill advised to let them take charge. Your emotions, in other words, should work for you, not the other way around. Luckily, emotional data are but one of multiple useful data sources to consult before deciding on a course of action.</p> <p>Your best move is to seek diverse consults from sources other than emotion before making important behavioral decisions. Such sources include your goals, values, experience, logic, knowledge of self and world, Google, and more. Having entertained the varied inputs, you can then make a well-considered (rather than emotionally driven) executive decision about your most sensible path forward.</p> <p>Consider an example: You’re driving to your daughter’s wedding when another driver cuts you off dangerously. Your anger flares, advising you to chase the driver down and retaliate. Your first correct move is to acknowledge your rage and its advice. Next, summon your other consultants: What’s your goal for this trip? What values are important for you to represent by your conduct? What are the odds for a productive highway confrontation? Then, make an executive decision about your best course of action.</p> <p>Odds are that you’ll recognize the folly of letting a stranger hijack this important day, that you will choose to honor your values (such as, say, nonviolence), and therefore politely decline anger’s advice and keep on your way. Your anger will have long dissipated by the time you’re wowing the inebriated wedding party with your fancy footwork on the dance floor.</p> <h2 id="tolerate-short-term-pain-to-avert-long-term-suffering">Tolerate Short-Term Pain to Avert Long-Term Suffering.</h2> <p>Which brings us to behavior, the domain where thoughts and emotions manifest most consequentially. The golden rule of healthy behavior management: Challenges exist. To be overcome they must be met. Enduring short-term discomfort is the necessary passport to long-term health and adaptation. Those who cannot tolerate acute temporary discomfort now condemn themselves to chronic suffering later.</p> <p>Of course, avoidant behavior is sometimes warranted, even necessary. It’s best to dodge, rather than confront, the oncoming train. But when avoidance is motivated by distorted thinking, emotional mismanagement, or our innate, dated distaste for delayed gratification and long-term calculations, then indulging it will prove destructive.</p> <p>Behavioral engagement, facing fears and challenges, is usually the better approach. It helps in several ways. First, it allows us to improve our understanding of the terrain and hone our skills. Many things we first perceive as difficult are not inherently hard but merely effortful because they’re new, and hence under control processes. Practice makes competence. And practice requires engagement.</p> <p>In addition, behavioral engagement tends to bring you into regular, productive contact with others, which may strengthen community ties and shore up your social support network. Human beings are social creatures. We thrive only in coherent, well-coordinated groups. Social connectedness is among the most powerful predictors of health, happiness and longevity. Engaging with others is a wise investment in your own well-being.</p> <p>Moreover, recent research by Mark Bouton, Michelle Craske, and others has shown that, unlike avoidance, the process of facing one’s fears lets new coping responses compete. It overrides earlier maladaptive habits when feared catastrophic predictions get refuted by actual benign experiences.</p> <p>Finally, behavioral engagement is useful because action begets emotion. Contrary to popular belief, the emotion-behavior link is reciprocal. At times, our actions may be emotionally driven. But other times, emotions are action driven.</p> <p>Just as feeling lusty may beget a couple’s make-out session, so will making out likely beget heightened lust (do try this at home). Our emotions often line up behind our actions. This is why, as David Ekers and others have shown, the practice of behavioral activation—intentionally engaging in activities one associates with positive memories and feelings—is an important part of effective treatment for mood disorders. The fastest, most reliable way to change how you feel is by changing what you do.</p> <p>In sum, doing basic mental health right entails practicing accurate thinking, emotion management, and behavioral engagement, while learning to tolerate short-term discomfort in the service of meaningful long-term goals and deeply held values. Such practice requires considerable effort and commitment, as do all things that matter. But the trouble is worth it because, to paraphrase my mother, at the end of the day, all you’ve got is your mental health.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Original Post: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/articles/202105/laws-of-emotional-mastery?msockid=3cc8053b5a536d851b73102d5b446c8c">Laws of Emotional Mastery</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>Copyright belongs to the original author.</em></strong></p> <hr style="border: 2px solid;"/> <h1 id="情绪掌控法则">情绪掌控法则</h1> <p>Noam Shpancer Ph.D. | 2021年5月4日 | 最后审阅于2022年8月16日</p> <p>生活，就像俗话所说的，像钻石一样——坚硬而美丽。 如今，许多人正深刻体会到它的坚硬，以压力、恐惧和疲惫的形式显现出来。 在应对这些困难时期时，我们成功与否很大程度上取决于我们的心理健康。</p> <p>人们可能会把心理健康想象成一个可以到达的地方，或是一个拥有的宝藏。 但心理健康既不是一个目的地，也不是一种财产。 相反，它是一种行为——正确心智管理的实践。</p> <p>你的心智很像一辆汽车：两者都充满能量；两者都能带你到达不同的地方；但两者也都可能偏离轨道，带来毁灭性的后果。 最重要的是，它们的有用性在很大程度上取决于你如何处理它们。</p> <p>良好的驾驶是一种不断适应的过程，它以高度的应变能力为特征，并需要掌握众多特定技能：如何转弯、融入车流、或安全变道。 同样，健全的心理健康是一种不断适应的过程，它以心理灵活性为特征——即能够识别和调整你的心态和行为，适应不同的情况，不至于冷酷地伤害自己或他人，并且在面对干扰和障碍时，依然能体现你的价值观，追求有意义的目标。</p> <p>像驾驶一样，心理健康的过程也需要一套特定的技能。 在这里，这些技能是帮助我们妥善管理心智产物的能力——我们的思想、情感和行为。 心理学为此提供了一些有用的指导。</p> <h2 id="准确思考">准确思考</h2> <p>晚上躺在床上时，你听到楼下传来一声突如其来的“砰”声。 你有什么感觉？你会做什么？ 你接下来的情绪和行动取决于你对这声响的解释。 如果你认为“这只是屋顶上的雪掉下来了”，你可能会毫不在意地继续睡觉。 但如果你认为“有小偷在窗边”，你可能会心跳加速，拿起手机或者枪，具体取决于你的观念。</p> <p>过去几十年的认知心理学研究表明，我们的想法——信念和主观解释——会引发我们的情绪和行为。 换句话说，思维对我们的情绪状态非常重要。</p> <p>一种常听到的建议是“要积极思考”。 积极思考的确有它的好处，适量时是有用的。 正如心理学家Martin Seligman和其他人的研究所示，乐观能帮助我们度过艰难时期，增强希望感，改善情绪。</p> <p>然而，尽管内容不同，积极思考的过程却与消极思考相似：它们都是偏见，都会掩盖和扭曲真相。 基于任何非真相的反应都存在巨大的风险。 如果你正在坠落，告诉自己学会飞行是没有用的。 由真相和事实引导的决策更有可能成功。 健康的心理状态需要精确的思维。</p> <p>思维就像病毒一样。 错误的思维一旦进入你的系统，可能会造成伤害。 糟糕的想法——例如种族主义——比病毒造成的伤害还要大。 而且它们更难根除。</p> <p>精确思考相当于非正式应用科学方法——根据证据对不同的真相主张进行裁定的过程。 为了培养精确思维的能力，我们必须首先认识到大脑的运作依赖于两个核心过程：控制过程和自动过程。 控制过程是缓慢的、费力的，且极易受到干扰；它们需要集中注意力和全神贯注。 自动过程则快速、抗干扰，不需要注意力或集中精神也能成功运作。</p> <p>学习驾驶是一种控制过程——费力且要求严格。 但十年后，你的驾驶已经变成自动化的——毫不费力且无需集中注意力。 这种自动化操作具有重要的进化意义：它们解放了能量，让有限的注意力资源能够集中于新的事物，帮助我们应对现实中的动态条件，从而更好地生存和发展。</p> <p>习惯是无意识中运行的自动化过程。 这一事实有两大含义。 首先，如果你没有意识到某件事，你就无法很好地描述它。 过程越自动化，我们获得的关于其运作的信息就越少——这就是为什么伟大的运动员往往不是伟大的教练。 他们反复做的事情已经自动化，他们不再清楚地知道自己是如何做到的。 其次，你无法改变你没有意识到的东西。 一个处于运行中的习惯会继续保持下去。</p> <p>我们一生中形成了许多“思维习惯”——对世界和自我的自动化思维方式。 功能性思维习惯——比如良好的饮食、睡眠或驾驶习惯——帮助我们高效且安全地运作。 但扭曲的思维习惯——如糟糕的饮食、睡眠或驾驶习惯——随着时间的推移，会导致心理痛苦和适应不良。</p> <p>例如，如果你形成了认为“任何不完美都是失败”的思维习惯，那么你很可能会经常评判自己为失败者，从而体验到心理上的痛苦。 你真正的问题不是不完美——不完美只是全人类的普遍状态，除了碧昂丝——而是那个扭曲的自动化信念：认为完美是唯一的成功形式。</p> <p>扭曲的思维习惯通常并非随机形成的，也不是由于某种思维异常而产生的，而是因为它们在形成时曾有过有用的作用。 例如，经过多年开车去上班的经历，你不需要注意路况。 这条路线已经自动化，允许你在通勤时让思绪自由飘散。 这是一个很好的适应性习惯。</p> <p>但如果你的办公室突然搬到城镇的另一端，那么同样的旧习惯就变得不再适应。 你将需要努力，集中注意力，并使用控制过程来学习新的路线。</p> <p>健全的心理维护同样需要识别并改变过时和无效的思维习惯。 做到这一点需要几个步骤。 首先，你需要意识到自己的思维习惯。 换句话说，你需要思考自己的思维，以便检测到反复出现的模式。 你可以通过问自己一些问题来做到这一点，比如：“我现在在对自己说什么？”或“在这种情况下我有什么想法？”</p> <p>第二步是要认识到，在某个特定情境中的初始想法只是旧习惯的作用，而不是被揭示的真理。 一般来说，想法不是世界事件，而是心智事件。 它们不是事实，而是假设，是对可能发生或不发生事情的推测。 因此，你可以以一种超然的、好奇的态度观察它们，并选择是否参与其中，或让它们像天上的云一样飘过。 这种超然的觉察有时本身就能中和那些困扰性思维的腐蚀性影响。</p> <p>意识到一个扭曲的思维习惯也使你能够改变它。 然而，仅有觉察是不够的：意识到某个地方存在并不会让你自动到达那里。 你不需要知道习惯是如何产生的，但要替代它，你需要积极地挑战和对抗旧的思维习惯。</p> <p>为此，你需要首先生成几种替代性思维。 问自己：“还有其他什么可能正在发生？”、“还有其他什么可能会发生？”、“在这里我还可以对自己说些什么？” 然后，根据证据来评估这些不同的想法。 （问自己：“如果必须的话，我愿意拿命来赌哪个想法？”或许会促使你寻找证据。） 最后，选择那个由最佳证据支持的想法。 然后不断对自己重复这个想法，并根据它采取行动。</p> <p>精确思维就像买眼镜。 你不会随便拿起第一副眼镜就买。 而是会检查商品，试戴几副，选择几个合适的候选，基于证据（如合适度、价格、款式、品牌等）进行比较，最终选择最适合你的那副。 你的眼镜如此，你的想法亦然。 最好在“购买”之前检查和评估“商品”。</p> <h2 id="既不否认也不服从接受情绪">既不否认也不服从——接受情绪</h2> <p>情绪对我们的生活有极大的影响，为我们的经历增添了色彩和味道。 但需要记住的是，情绪和思想一样，都是心智事件，而非世界事件，这意味着我们在调节情绪方面有很大的自主权。</p> <p>科学尚未完全解开情绪体验的本质、结构和起源。 但我们知道的是，从实用的角度来看，情绪是一种数据，通常在应对世界时非常有用。 一定程度的情绪激动可以帮助我们学习新事物并记住重要事件。 婴儿的哭声有效地吸引了看护者的注意。 恐惧则让你远离悬崖的危险边缘。</p> <p>然而，正如任何数据一样，情绪体验也面临着两个重要问题： 首先，这些数据是否可靠，或者它们是否在某种重要方面不完整、被破坏或歪曲？ 其次，鉴于这些数据，最好的回应是什么？</p> <p>心理学家David Barlow等人的研究表明，心理痛苦往往不是由情绪体验本身引起的，而是源于情绪调节的错误——也就是处理数据的错误。 第一个常见的错误是“否认”，即抗拒、拒绝或回避情绪。 这发生在你告诉自己不允许感受某种情绪时。 例如，在一个重要演讲前感到紧张时，你责备自己不该焦虑。</p> <p>否认情绪的冲动，尤其是负面情绪，是可以理解的。 负面情绪不令人愉快，我们常将它们与负面的事件和结果联系起来，并希望避免或忘记这些情绪。 事实上，George Vaillant等人的研究表明，一定程度的有意识情绪抑制——选择不去参与或讨论令人痛苦的情感——常常是一种有用且健康的应对机制。 然而，这种抑制需要意识、接受，并且不惧怕面对情绪。</p> <p>另一方面，否认则意味着一种对情绪的恐惧和不愿感受。 试图否认情绪是无效的，原因有很多。 首先，我们的内在结构中有一条规律：无论你告诉自己不允许感受或思考什么，你已经在感受和思考了。 抗拒情绪因此是徒劳的，就像逆着强流游泳一样不明智且令人疲惫。</p> <p>此外，将某种情绪标记为“禁忌”、“不可容忍”或“危险”可能会让你对正试图否认的情绪保持高度警觉。 对即将到来的负面体验的持续警惕本身就变成了一种负面体验。</p> <p>最后，否认负面情绪的习惯可能会随着时间的推移演变成“体验性回避”，即一种回避困难内心经历的普遍倾向。 Steven Hayes等人的研究发现，体验性回避是许多心理病理学的潜在因素，有多个原因导致这种现象。</p> <p>即使在最好的时候，生活也是一场障碍赛。 保持方向并实现有意义的目标需要愿意面对和克服逆境。 如果你面对困难时的唯一反应是退缩，你最终将逃避整个生活。 无法忍受艰难情绪会让你的心理生活变得贫乏。</p> <p>回避之所以吸引人，是因为它能迅速带来缓解。 人类大脑倾向于偏爱短期计算和即时满足。 摆在我们眼前的奖励比遥远的后果更为吸引人。 一桶油炸薯条就在我面前，这使它更具诱惑力，而未来几年后的心脏病发作则是模糊的、难以想象的。 难怪我会伸手去拿那桶薯条。</p> <p>在我们这一物种的早期环境中，生活是短期的，不稳定的。 优先考虑即时奖励是适应性的。 而现在的生活——如果幸运的话——是长期的，需要长期策略。 在水下屏住呼吸可以在短期内让你活下来，但对于长时间潜水来说，这不是有效的策略。 同样，回避的习惯在短期内有效，但随着时间的推移就会变得不适应。</p> <p>回避不会教会你如何应对，反而会让你学会更多地逃避，因此回避行为会随着时间的推移而扩散。 你回避得越多，你就变得越不称职、越缺乏知识和自信，你能真正体验到的生活也就越少。</p> <p>处理情绪时的第二个常见错误可以称为“情绪服从”。 我们假设情绪代表着真相、全部的真相，并且必须驱动我们的行为：“我害怕，所以我必须逃跑。” “我生气了，所以我必须战斗。”</p> <p>这种情绪驱动的行为是有问题的，因为研究表明——通过自我反思你也会确认——我们的情绪往往提供的是扭曲的、片面的、带有偏见的信息。 坐过山车时的恐惧可能是真实的，但实际上并没有真正的危险，除了可能弄乱了发型。 我们更害怕的东西（比如飞机、陌生人）往往比我们不那么害怕的东西（比如汽车、家人）更安全。 你喝醉后坚持自己状态良好、可以开车就是一个明显的例子。</p> <p>即使情绪讲述了一个真实的故事，它们也很少能展现事情的全貌。 你对买房子的感受固然重要，但在选择住所时，这并不是唯一的考虑因素。 预算、家庭规模、社区、市场状况以及其他可选方案都同样重要，往往更重要。</p> <p>要恰当地调节情绪数据，我们必须避免否认情绪或服从情绪。 相反，有一个简单的两步过程。 第一步是接受。 情绪在某种意义上是内在的天气，我们对待情绪的态度应该像对待天气一样，接受它们的真实和事实。 如果你感到焦虑或悲伤，最好的第一步就是承认并接受你的情绪：“我是人类，人类有情绪。这种情绪是我目前体验的一部分。”</p> <p>接受带来好处。 它是一种面对事实的方式，就像诚实地描述一件困难的事件。 这样做可能很难，但它展现了你的勇气，并增强了你的力量。 通过接受你的情绪，你也接受了你所处情境的事实，这为你成功应对提供了基础。</p> <p>接受情绪也消除了否认情绪所需的使人疲惫不堪的、徒劳的努力，并为你提供了机会去审视和了解自己的一部分经历。 知识就是力量。 自我认知就是自我赋能。</p> <p>最后，接受负面情绪减少了它的破坏性潜力。 陷入激流时，最好的做法不是抵抗，而是让水流把你带到海里。 很快，水流就会减弱并散去，你就能绕过它安全地游回岸边。</p> <p>接受并不意味着盲目服从情绪。 相反，情绪管理的下一步是决定如何处理情绪数据。 一旦你承认下雨了，还是由你来决定如何应对这个事实。</p> <p>情绪往往是好的顾问，但却是糟糕的执行者。 我们应考虑情绪的建议，但不应让它们掌控一切。 换句话说，你的情绪应该为你服务，而不是你为情绪服务。 幸运的是，情绪数据只是多个有用数据源之一，我们可以在做出行为决策前参考其他数据。</p> <p>在做重要决策前，你的最佳做法是从情绪以外的来源寻找多样化的建议。 这些来源包括你的目标、价值观、经验、逻辑、对自我和世界的了解、以及谷歌等等。 在吸收了多种意见后，你可以做出经过深思熟虑的（而非情绪驱动的）决策，找出最合理的行动路径。</p> <p>举个例子：你正在开车去参加女儿的婚礼，这时另一辆车危险地从你面前插了进来。 你的愤怒情绪燃起，建议你追上这辆车报复。 正确的第一步是承认你的愤怒以及它的建议。 接着，传唤其他顾问的：你这次旅行的目标是什么？你希望通过自己的行为表现哪些价值观？高速路上的对峙有多大可能是有效的？ 然后，做出关于最佳行动方案的决策。</p> <p>你很可能会认识到让一个陌生人劫持这重要一天的愚蠢之处，选择尊重你的价值观（例如，非暴力），因此礼貌地拒绝愤怒的建议，继续前行。 等到你在舞池上用华丽的舞步让醉酒的婚礼宾客惊叹时，你的愤怒早已消散。</p> <h2 id="忍受短期痛苦以避免长期痛苦">忍受短期痛苦以避免长期痛苦</h2> <p>这就引出了行为问题，这是思想和情绪最能展现影响力的领域。 健康行为管理的黄金法则是：挑战存在。 要克服它们，就必须面对它们。 忍受短期的不适是实现长期健康和适应的必要通行证。 那些现在无法忍受短暂的急性不适的人，最终将自己置于长期痛苦之中。</p> <p>当然，回避行为有时是合理的，甚至是必要的。 面对迎面而来的火车，最好是躲开，而不是迎面相对。 但当回避行为是由扭曲的思维、情绪失调或我们与生俱来的、已经过时的对延迟满足和长期规划的厌恶所驱动时，纵容这种行为将会带来破坏性后果。</p> <p>行为上的参与，即面对恐惧和挑战，通常是更好的方法。 它的好处有很多。 首先，它让我们更好地了解环境并磨练我们的技能。 许多我们最初认为困难的事情，并非天生就难，而是因为它们是新的，因此需要控制性过程来完成。 练习带来能力。 而练习需要参与。</p> <p>此外，行为参与往往能让你与他人保持定期、富有成效的接触，这可能会加强社区联系并巩固你的社会支持网络。 人类是社会性生物。 我们只有在协作良好、组织有序的群体中才能茁壮成长。 社会连接是健康、幸福和长寿的最强有力的预测指标之一。 与他人的互动是对自己健康的明智投资。</p> <p>此外，Mark Bouton, Michelle Craske等人的最新研究表明，面对恐惧的过程让新的应对反应得以竞争。 当人们预测的灾难性后果被实际的良性体验所推翻时，它会取代早期的不适应习惯。</p> <p>最后，行为参与之所以有用，是因为行动能产生情绪。 与普遍看法相反，情绪与行为的联系是双向的。 有时我们的行为是由情绪驱动的，但在其他时候，情绪是由行为驱动的。</p> <p>就像感受到欲望可能会引发情侣的亲热行为，而亲热行为反过来也可能会增加欲望一样（确保是在家中尝试确）。 我们的情绪往往会跟随我们的行为。 正因如此，正如David Ekers等人所展示的那样，“行为激活”实践——有意识地从事与积极记忆和感受相关的活动——是有效治疗情绪障碍的重要部分。 改变情绪最快、最可靠的方法就是改变你的行为。</p> <p>总而言之，正确的心理健康实践包括准确思维、情绪管理和行为参与，同时学习忍受短期不适，以实现有意义的长期目标和深植于心的价值观。 这种实践需要大量的努力和投入，正如所有重要的事情一样。 但这种努力是值得的，因为，借用我母亲的话来说，到了最后，你所拥有的就是你的心理健康。</p> <hr/> <p><strong>原文链接: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/articles/202105/laws-of-emotional-mastery?msockid=3cc8053b5a536d851b73102d5b446c8c">Laws of Emotional Mastery</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>版权属于原作者，本翻译仅供学习用途。</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="repost"/><category term="phycology"/><category term="emotions"/><category term="CHN Available"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mental health doesn’t just happen. Like physical fitness, it takes effort. Three principles spell the difference between just surviving and outright thriving.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4 Things to Do When You’re Burning Out at Work</title><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/4-things-to-do-when-youre-burning-out-at-work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Things to Do When You’re Burning Out at Work"/><published>2024-10-14T17:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T17:02:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/4-things-to-do-when-youre-burning-out-at-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/4-things-to-do-when-youre-burning-out-at-work/"><![CDATA[<p>Susan Biali Haas M.D. | Posted July 19, 2019 | Reviewed by Gary Drevitch</p> <p>I first experienced severe burnout (and overlapping depression) years ago, when I was an Emergency Medicine resident. I never wanted to hit bottom that hard ever again and decided to learn everything I could about resilience and mental wellness.</p> <p>I started working as a coach over a decade ago, helping busy, overwhelmed women create more balanced, meaningful lives. Almost every client has some sort of work-related stress they need help with. Over the last few years, most are either on the edge of burnout or in the throes of severe work-related depletion.</p> <p>Many are so fed up that they hire me to help them ditch their current position and find something else.</p> <p>If possible, I counsel clients to wait and try smaller changes first. If you’re suffering from true burnout, you’re emotionally and mentally exhausted and not in a good zone to make life-altering decisions.</p> <p>Here’s what I advise clients to do:</p> <p><strong>1. Identify what’s causing you the most stress, and see if there’s a solution.</strong></p> <p>Maslach and Leiter, leading researchers on the subject of burnout, determined that there are six areas of work-life that can lead to burnout: excess workloads, lack of control, insufficient rewards, workplace community issues, unfair practices, and value conflicts.</p> <p>I’m working with a client who exhibits almost all the signs of burnout. She’s seriously considering leaving her position, though she used to love her work and still loves the company. In cases like hers, I’m concerned that thoughts of leaving are almost exclusively burnout-related.</p> <p>Some very specific issues are pushing her over the edge. Rather than sending in her resignation, she asked her superiors if they could make key changes. They highly value her and have agreed to respond to her requests. If they do, the positive impact will be significant, and far more convenient than having to chase down new work.</p> <p><strong>2. Stop doing work that’s not yours.</strong></p> <p>Excess workloads are one of the most common causes of burnout. When I ask clients where they might be able to cut back, the usual response is “Nowhere!” My next question: “Is there anything you’re doing at work that’s really someone else’s responsibility?”</p> <p>There almost always is. Highly conscientious people are at high risk for burnout, and they’re usually doing other people’s work. They want to help (rescue) others, or have a hard time saying no. Or perfectionism has entered in: The other person won’t do the task as well as they can, even though it’s not their responsibility.</p> <p>If you’re overwhelmed with work, look at everything you’re doing, and then get rid of anything you don’t actually have to do.</p> <p><strong>3. Place hard boundaries between work and the rest of your life.</strong></p> <p>Another client feels extremely stressed and burdened by her job, with little to no time for herself. She starts early, works long hours, and usually works into the evening at home. She doesn’t actually have to, but she feels continually pressured and ends up working in her off hours by default.</p> <p>When I asked her what she might do about this, her response was immediate: “I can leave my laptop at work! That way when I’m at home, I’ll be forced to do something else.” Perfect. I’ve had other clients do similar things, such as putting their work phone in a drawer—not to be touched—over weekends.</p> <p>How might you draw clearer boundaries between work and home?</p> <p><strong>4. Start taking care of yourself physically.</strong></p> <p>If you’re getting less than seven hours of sleep a night, you’re likely to feel exhausted and fried. If you’re skipping breakfast, mainlining espresso and grabbing junk food all day to keep yourself going, you’ll be sure to feel awful and perform even worse. If you sit at a desk all day without breaks and never get any exercise, it’s not surprising that you feel irritable and stressed.</p> <p>If you’re scrimping on sleep, not eating properly, or hardly moving at all in a given day, this is good news to me as a coach, because I know that as soon as you begin to get more regular sleep, eat better, and get moving, you’ll feel dramatically better. You might even start liking your job again.</p> <p>As I always say, if you feel like you’re burning out it’s important to see your doctor or a qualified psychological professional. (This post is not intended to replace their advice). As I personally experienced, burnout can overlap with depression. Some experts even believe that burnout is a work-related form of depression. Other medical conditions can also present with similar symptoms. Life’s too short to feel continually stressed and at the end of your rope. Try these steps to take your life back, and see how much better you feel.</p> <p><strong>Original Post: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/prescriptions-for-life/201907/4-things-to-do-when-youre-burning-out-at-work">4 Things to Do When You’re Burning Out at Work</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>Copyright belongs to the original author.</em></strong></p> <hr style="border: 2px solid;"/> <h1 id="应对工作倦怠的四个方法">应对工作倦怠的四个方法</h1> <p>Susan Biali Haas M.D. | 2019年7月19日 | 审阅：Gary Drevitch</p> <p>几年前，当我还是急诊医学住院医生时，我第一次经历了严重的倦怠（伴随着抑郁症）。 我再也不想跌入如此深的谷底，于是决定学习所有与韧性和心理健康相关的知识。</p> <p>十多年前，我开始作为教练工作，帮助忙碌且不堪重负的女性创造更加平衡、有意义的生活。 几乎每个客户都需要帮助应对某种与工作相关的压力。 在过去的几年里，大多数客户要么处在倦怠的边缘，要么深陷严重的工作疲惫中。</p> <p>很多人厌倦到了极点，他们雇我来帮助他们摆脱当前的职位，寻找其他工作。</p> <p>如果可能，我会建议客户先等待，并尝试做一些小的改变。 如果你正遭受真正的倦怠，你在情感和心理上都已经非常疲惫，不适合做出改变生活的重大决定。</p> <p>以下是我建议客户采取的步骤：</p> <p><strong>1. 找出是什么让你最感压力，并看看是否有解决方案。</strong></p> <p>倦怠领域的领军研究者Maslach和Leiter发现，有六个工作生活领域可能导致倦怠：工作负荷过重、缺乏控制、奖励不足、工作社区问题、不公平的做法和价值冲突。</p> <p>我正在和一位几乎表现出所有倦怠迹象的客户合作。 她正在认真考虑辞职，尽管她曾经热爱她的工作，仍然喜欢这家公司。 像她这样的情况，我担心她的离职想法几乎完全是由倦怠驱动的。</p> <p>一些非常具体的问题正在将她推向边缘。 她没有提交辞呈，而是向上级提出是否可以进行关键的改变。 他们非常重视她，已经同意回应她的请求。 如果他们的改变能够落实，带来的积极影响将是巨大的，比寻找新工作要方便得多。</p> <p><strong>2. 停止做不属于你的工作。</strong></p> <p>工作负荷过重是导致倦怠最常见的原因之一。 当我问客户他们在哪些方面可以减少工作量时，通常的回答是：“没有！” 我的下一个问题是：“你有没有在做本该是别人的工作？”</p> <p>几乎总是有的。 有高度责任感的人很容易倦怠，他们通常在做别人的工作。 他们想要帮助（拯救）他人，或者难以拒绝请求。 或者，完美主义作祟：虽然这不是他们的责任，但他们觉得别人做不好这项任务。</p> <p>如果你感到工作负担过重，审视一下你在做的所有工作，然后剔除掉那些你实际上不必做的工作。</p> <p><strong>3. 在工作和生活之间设定明确的界限。</strong></p> <p>另一位客户感到工作压力大，负担沉重，几乎没有属于自己的时间。 她每天早早开始工作，工作很长时间，通常会在晚上回到家后继续工作。 她其实不需要这样做，但总是感到有压力，最终默认在下班时间也在工作。</p> <p>当我问她可以怎么改变这种情况时，她立刻回答：“我可以把笔记本电脑留在公司！这样我回家时就被迫去做别的事情。” 完美的解决方案。 我有其他客户采取过类似的做法，比如把工作手机放在抽屉里——整个周末都不会碰它。</p> <p>你如何在工作和家庭之间划出更明确的界限？</p> <p><strong>4. 开始照顾好自己的身体。</strong></p> <p>如果你每晚睡眠时间不足七小时，你很可能会感到精疲力尽。 如果你跳过早餐、靠浓缩咖啡维持精力并整天吃垃圾食品，你一定会感觉糟糕，工作表现也会变得更差。 如果你整天坐在办公桌前，没有任何休息时间，也不进行锻炼，那么你感到易怒和压力大也就不足为奇了。</p> <p>如果你睡眠不足、饮食不规律或者一天几乎不运动，作为教练，我反倒觉得这是好消息，因为我知道，一旦你开始规律睡眠、饮食改善并多动起来，你会感觉好得多。 你甚至可能重新喜欢上你的工作。</p> <p>正如我常说的，如果你觉得自己快要倦怠，重要的是去看医生或合格的心理专家。 （这篇文章并非旨在取代他们的建议）。 正如我个人经历的那样，倦怠可能伴随有抑郁症。 一些专家甚至认为倦怠是一种与工作相关的抑郁症。 其他医学状况也可能表现出类似的症状。 生活太短暂了，不应该让自己总是感到压力重重、走投无路。 尝试这些步骤来找回你的生活，看看自己感觉会好多少。</p> <p><strong>原文链接: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/prescriptions-for-life/201907/4-things-to-do-when-youre-burning-out-at-work">4 Things to Do When You’re Burning Out at Work</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>版权属于原作者，本翻译仅供学习用途。</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="repost"/><category term="phycology"/><category term="burnout"/><category term="CHN Available"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Burned out? These four steps could turn things around for you.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Are You Burned Out or Just Exhausted?</title><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/are-you-burned-out-or-just-exhausted/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are You Burned Out or Just Exhausted?"/><published>2024-10-14T17:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T17:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/are-you-burned-out-or-just-exhausted</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/are-you-burned-out-or-just-exhausted/"><![CDATA[<p>Paula Davis J.D., M.A.P.P. | Posted August 14, 2023 | Reviewed by Devon Frye</p> <p>How is your well-being at work? Heavy workloads, stressful jobs, and long work hours continue to leave employees at all levels feeling exhausted. In fact, Deloitte’s 2023 Workplace Well-Being Report found that 60 percent of employees, 64 percent of managers, and 75 percent of the C-suite are seriously considering quitting their jobs for one that would better support their well-being.</p> <p>But does that mean employees are burned out? Not so fast.</p> <p>The term burnout tends to be oversimplified as an individual failing of stress management and used interchangeably with exhaustion or overwhelm; however, burnout consists of more than just exhaustion. Burnout exists on a continuum that consists of these three dimensions:</p> <ol> <li>Chronic exhaustion (feeling physically and emotionally drained, tired, overwhelmed, and overloaded more often than not); and</li> <li>Chronic cynicism (people in your work world bother you and annoy you, and you may start to distance yourself from your colleagues and clients, ignoring the qualities that make them unique and engaging, resulting in less empathy); and</li> <li>Inefficacy (the “why bother, who cares” mentality that appears as you struggle to identify important work resources and begin to feel ineffective at work).</li> </ol> <p>This means that you can be exhausted only, feel cynical or frustrated only, or feel disconnected or disengaged from your work only; or, any number of other combinations. That’s important because the measurement of burnout also tends to be oversimplified.</p> <p>Drs. Christina Maslach and Michael Leiter, pioneers in burnout research and two of the developers of the Maslach Burnout Inventory, an empirically validated assessment tool that measures all three of the burnout components above, have issued updated guidance about what constitutes a “burnout profile.” According to their research, to earn the label “burnout,” a person must experience high exhaustion, high cynicism, and low professional efficacy. Based on their work, only about 20 percent of workers fit this profile.</p> <p>While I think that number is low, surveys that simply ask people, “Do you feel burned out?” are likely over-inflating burnout rates since most people equate burnout with exhaustion and therefore respond “yes” because they feel overwhelmed, stressed, or tired. As an example, the Wellbeing Lab in Australia found that 63.6 percent of Australian workers reported feeling burned out, but that level dropped to 21.2 percent when measured using the three dimensions above.</p> <p>If you’re feeling exhausted, but not yet burned out, here are some ideas to help:</p> <p><strong>1. List your job demands and resources.</strong></p> <p>Burnout is more likely to happen when you have too many job demands (aspects of your work that are consistently energy-draining) and too few job resources (aspects of your work that are consistently energy-giving). The two columns don’t have to be equal, but you do need enough energy-giving aspects of your work to mitigate the stress of the demands. What additional resources do you need?</p> <p><strong>2. Intentional prioritization.</strong></p> <p>A real estate developer client of mine used to prioritize his legal work for me using the terms, “nuclear,” “super nuclear,” and “catastrophic.” It still makes me laugh because it all sounds urgent and never gave me any clear guidance.</p> <p>Instead, I suggest trying this prioritization exercise I learned from the Luma Institute:</p> <p>Make a list of all of the projects, matters, and items you need to prioritize. Put one project, matter, or item on a sticky note until you have them all listed (one project per sticky note). Grab a large piece of paper and make a quad chart (four boxes in a 2x2 matrix). Label the horizontal axis “Importance” and label the vertical axis “Difficulty.” Plot items horizontally by importance and plot items vertically by difficulty. Look for related groupings and set priorities. Target the items in the lower right quadrant first because they are highly important and can be accomplished with relative ease.</p> <p><strong>3. Know your narratives.</strong></p> <p>Your “narratives” are your core values and beliefs about the way you think the world should operate. Not labeling these narratives can frustrate your ability to manage stress and prioritize your well-being. Here are some examples of common narratives I hear among busy professionals:</p> <ul> <li>“I must have all the answers.”</li> <li>“If I can’t do something perfectly, then I shouldn’t do it at all.”</li> <li>“Failure is a sign of weakness.”</li> <li>“Strong people don’t ask for help.”</li> <li>“Taking a break is a sign of laziness.” (This is one of my own!)</li> <li>“In order to be at the top of my game, I must always/never _______.”</li> </ul> <p>Narratives become rules you live by (oftentimes subconsciously) and are usually too inflexible to help you perform in an optimal way. The first step is identifying your narratives and rules; the second is evaluating them.</p> <p>Ask: Is this narrative getting me closer to or further away from the goals I want to achieve? How could I reshape the rule to make it a little more flexible? This is deep self-awareness work, but researcher Nick Petrie and his colleagues have discovered that it’s one of the best ways to prevent burnout (and a necessary step to get out of it).</p> <p><strong>4. Give yourself a break.</strong></p> <p>Just like remembering your small wins can increase motivation, overthinking small setbacks can kill it. Self-compassion is the art and science of giving yourself a break, and it can help prevent burnout. When you experience a setback, this framework will save you some much-needed energy:</p> <ol> <li>When you feel stressed, take a moment to describe the emotions you’re feeling. Do you feel self-critical, and if so, what do you say to yourself? Evaluating the emotions (which isn’t always easy) helps you better understand what you’re feeling before you rush to escape.</li> <li>Normalize the setback. You’re not the only person who has forgotten a key piece of information in a presentation or been frustrated with a colleague. Setbacks happen to everyone, but it’s tempting to think you’re the only one.</li> <li>What would you say to a friend who experienced the same setback? We beat ourselves up tremendously when we fail, but would you be just as harsh if your friend approached you with the same set of circumstances?</li> </ol> <p>Burnout rates are currently at the same level as their peak during the pandemic. I have spent the past several years working with teams and leaders around the globe to both educate and help solve this problem.</p> <p>Last year was my first year running my business and traveling for a full slate of programs as a single mom, a variable I highly underestimated. By December, I wondered ironically, “Am I burned out?” Once I asked myself about all three burnout factors, I quickly realized that I was simply exhausted.</p> <p>Not every experience of stress—even chronic stress—is burnout. Correctly identifying how you experience workplace stress is the first step toward feeling better.</p> <p><strong>Original Post: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/pressure-proof/202308/are-you-burned-out-or-just-exhausted">Are You Burned Out or Just Exhausted?</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>Copyright belongs to the original author.</em></strong></p> <hr style="border: 2px solid;"/> <h1 id="你是倦怠还是只是疲惫">你是倦怠还是只是疲惫？</h1> <p>Paula Davis J.D., M.A.P.P. | 2023年8月14日 | 审阅：Devon Frye</p> <p>你的工作状况如何？ 繁重的工作负担、压力大的工作和长时间的工作仍然让各级员工感到筋疲力尽。 事实上，德勤2023年工作场所健康报告发现，60%的员工、64%的管理者和75%的高管正在认真考虑辞职，以寻找一份能更好支持其身心健康的工作。</p> <p>但这是否意味着员工已经精疲力竭？ 不一定。</p> <p>“倦怠”一词往往被过度简化为个人无法管理压力的表现，常与疲惫或不堪重负等词互换使用；然而，倦怠远不止是疲惫。</p> <p>倦怠存在于一个由以下三个维度组成的连续体中：</p> <ol> <li>持续的疲惫（感到身心俱疲、疲倦、压力大、负荷过重，且这种感觉经常出现）；以及</li> <li>持续的冷漠（你工作中的人让你感到烦躁，你可能开始疏远同事和客户，忽略他们的独特之处，导致同理心减少）；以及</li> <li>无效感（你可能产生“为什么要费心，谁在乎”的想法，难以识别重要的工作资源，开始觉得自己在工作中无能为力）。</li> </ol> <p>这意味着你可能只是感到疲惫，或者仅仅感到冷漠或沮丧，或只是感到与工作脱节或失去参与感；或者，这些感受以各种不同的组合出现。 这很重要，因为倦怠的测量往往也被过度简化了。</p> <p>倦怠研究的先驱者，Maslach博士和Leiter博士是Maslach倦怠量表的开发者之一，这是一种经过验证的评估工具，用来测量上述倦怠的三个组成部分。 两位专家为“倦怠状态”提供了新的指导意见。 根据他们的研究，要被称为“倦怠”，一个人必须经历高度的疲惫、高度的冷漠和较低的职业效能感。 基于他们的工作，只有大约20%的员工符合这个倦怠状态的标准。</p> <p>虽然我认为这个比例较低，但那些仅仅询问人们“你是否感到倦怠？”的调查可能夸大了倦怠率，因为大多数人将倦怠等同于疲惫，因此回答“是”，因为他们感到不堪重负、压力大或疲惫。 例如，澳大利亚的Wellbeing Lab发现，63.6%的澳大利亚工人报告感到倦怠，但当使用上述三个维度进行测量时，这一比例下降到了21.2%。</p> <p>如果你感到疲惫，但还没有达到倦怠的程度，这里有一些建议可以帮助你：</p> <p><strong>1. 列出你的工作需求和资源。</strong></p> <p>当你的工作需求过多（工作中持续消耗精力的方面）而工作资源过少（工作中持续提供能量的方面）时，倦怠更有可能发生。 这两列不需要完全平衡，但你确实需要足够的工作资源来缓解工作需求带来的压力。 你还需要哪些额外的资源？</p> <p><strong>2. 有意的优先排序。</strong></p> <p>我曾经有一个房地产开发商客户，他用“核爆级”、“超级核爆级”和“灾难级”来优先排序他为我准备的法律工作。 这仍然让我发笑，因为这些都听起来很紧急，但并没有给我明确的指导。</p> <p>相反，我建议尝试Luma Institute教给我的这个优先排序练习：</p> <ul> <li>列出你所有需要优先处理的项目、事项和工作。把每个项目、事项或工作写在一张便签纸上，直到你把它们都列出来（每张便签纸上只写一个项目）。</li> <li>拿一张大纸，做一个四象限图（2x2矩阵的四个框）。</li> <li>将横轴标记为“重要性”，将纵轴标记为“难度”。</li> <li>按照重要性水平横向排列项目，并根据难度水平纵向排列项目。</li> <li>寻找相关的分组，并设定优先级。</li> </ul> <p>优先处理右下象限的项目，因为它们非常重要且相对容易完成。</p> <p><strong>3. 了解你的叙事。</strong></p> <p>你的“叙事”是你对世界应该如何运作的核心价值观和信念。 如果不标记这些叙述，它们可能会阻碍你管理压力和优先考虑自己的健康。 以下是我在繁忙的专业人士中经常听到的一些常见叙述：</p> <ul> <li>“我必须知道所有的答案。”</li> <li>“如果不能做到完美，我就不应该去做。”</li> <li>“失败是软弱的表现。”</li> <li>“坚强的人不会寻求帮助。”</li> <li>“休息是懒惰的表现。”（这是我自己的！）</li> <li>“为了保持最佳状态，我必须始终/绝不_______。”</li> </ul> <p>这些叙述成为你生活的规则（通常是潜意识的），并且往往过于僵化，无法帮助你以最佳方式工作。 第一步是识别你的叙述和规则；第二步是评估它们。</p> <p>问自己：这个叙述是否让我更接近或更远离我想要实现的目标？ 如何重新塑造这条规则，使其稍微灵活一些？ 这是一项深层次的自我意识工作，但研究员Nick Petrie及其同事发现，这是预防倦怠的最佳方法之一（也是摆脱倦怠的必要步骤）。</p> <p><strong>4. 给自己一个喘息的机会。</strong></p> <p>正如记住小小的胜利可以增加动力一样，过度思考小小的挫折则会扼杀动力。 自我关怀是一门艺术和科学，能够帮助你在需要时给自己一个喘息的机会，从而预防倦怠。 当你遇到挫折时，这个框架可以帮你节省宝贵的能量：</p> <ol> <li>当你感到压力时，花点时间描述你正在体验的情绪。你是否感到自责？如果是，你会对自己说些什么？评估这些情绪（这并不总是容易的）有助于你在急于逃避之前更好地理解自己的感受。</li> <li>正常化挫折。你不是唯一一个在演讲中忘记关键信息或对同事感到沮丧的人。挫折每个人都会遇到，但我们往往认为自己是唯一的例外。</li> <li>如果你的朋友遇到了同样的挫折，你会对他说些什么？当我们失败时，我们往往对自己非常苛刻，但如果你的朋友以同样的情况向你求助，你会同样苛刻吗？</li> </ol> <p>目前的倦怠率与疫情期间的峰值相同。 过去几年，我一直在与全球各地的团队和领导者合作，既进行教育，也帮助解决这个问题。</p> <p>去年是我第一次作为单身母亲经营自己的业务，并为一整年的项目安排旅行，我严重低估了这个变量。 到12月时，我不禁自嘲地问：“我是不是倦怠了？” 一旦我问自己这三个倦怠因素，我很快意识到自己只是疲惫而已。</p> <p>并非所有的压力体验（即使是长期压力）都是倦怠。 正确识别你在工作场所体验压力的方式是改善感觉的第一步。</p> <p><strong>原文链接: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/pressure-proof/202308/are-you-burned-out-or-just-exhausted">Are You Burned Out or Just Exhausted?</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>版权属于原作者，本翻译仅供学习用途。</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="repost"/><category term="phycology"/><category term="burnout"/><category term="CHN Available"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What you need to recover from each is different.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Basic and Complex Emotions</title><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/basic-and-complex-emotions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basic and Complex Emotions"/><published>2024-10-14T00:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T00:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/basic-and-complex-emotions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/basic-and-complex-emotions/"><![CDATA[<p>Berit Brogaard D.M.Sci., Ph.D | Posted June 30, 2018 | Reviewed by Jessica Schrader</p> <p>It is commonplace in philosophy and psychology to divide emotions into two groups: basic and complex emotions.</p> <p>Complex emotions, such as grief, regret, and jealousy, have highly variable appearances and compositions.</p> <p>Basic emotions, which include sadness, anger, fear, disgust, contempt, joy, and surprise, are so-called because they are associated with universally recognizable facial expressions (see image). In disgust, for example, you see a raised upper lip, a wrinkled nose bridge, and raised cheeks.</p> <p>Although basic emotions are sometimes accompanied by unique facial expressions and behavioral responses, there is no one-one correspondence between emotions and how they appear. Take the universally recognizable facial expressions. Very talented actors can mimic these facial expressions without having the associated emotion. Conversely, most of us are masters in suppressing facial expressions accompanying emotions. You might feel genuinely sad, yet put on a big smile before entering your workplace, thereby deceiving your colleagues into thinking that you are cheerful.</p> <p>Even when our emotional expressions reflect our inner mental life, they need not be universally recognizable. This is because the basic emotions can trigger many other expressions besides the unique facial expressions, physiological responses, and tendencies to act. Examples:</p> <ol> <li>Intense sadness might give rise to a facial expression nearly indistinguishable from anger or rage.</li> <li>Mild sadness may not look like anything at all.</li> <li>When several emotions are simultaneously present, one of the emotions may dominate and show up on your face.</li> <li>When emotions last for a long time, they pop in and out of your conscious awareness. When you are not aware of them, It is much harder to detect them.</li> </ol> <p>Basic emotions likely have made significant contributions to our survival since the beginning of human history. When understood in this sense, “basic”—as it occurs in “basic emotion”—just means primordial (evolutionarily basic).</p> <p>But if an emotion is truly basic, how could it have more basic components? Take surprise. We can split surprise into two responses: one is a positive sense of interest and wonder, and the other is a negative feeling of panic. Why call surprise “basic” when it’s composed of other emotions?</p> <p>The reason for this is that “basic” does not mean “lacks components.”</p> <p>In fact, complex emotions vary a lot in what they are like in different people, situations, and cultures. Although grief is often taken to be a blend of surprise, denial, sadness and anger, grief can be entirely different in some people or cultures. For example, some people grieve a loss without ever showing anger. Others grieve by being absolutely furious.</p> <p>Grief is often said to be composed of surprise, denial, bargaining, fear, anger, sadness, and acceptance. These components are not usually present all at the same time during a grieving episode but tend to occur sequentially and not necessarily in the order I just listed them in. Although grief can involve these building blocks, it can be manifested in numerous other ways. If the loss was expected, surprise may not be a component. If you are grieving the death of a loved one, the grief may not involve denial or bargaining. If, by contrast, you are grieving a breakup, you may go through long periods of denying that the breakup really is a breakup and ferociously negotiate and bargain with your ex. Grief can also involve alterations in mood, including feelings of depression, despair, melancholy, irritability or anxiety as well as temporary changes in the manifest features of personality, for instance, shifting toward isolation, insecurity, emotionality, and vigilance.</p> <p>It’s likely because complex emotions can be a blend of different mental states in different people, situations and cultures that they do not give rise to a facial expression that is universally recognized.</p> <p><strong>Original Post: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-superhuman-mind/201807/basic-and-complex-emotions">Basic and Complex Emotions</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>Copyright belongs to the original author.</em></strong></p> <hr style="border: 2px solid;"/> <h1 id="基本情绪和复杂情绪">基本情绪和复杂情绪</h1> <p>Berit Brogaard D.M.Sci., Ph.D | 2018年6月30日 | 审阅：Jessica Schrader</p> <p>在哲学和心理学中，情绪通常被分为两类：基本情绪和复杂情绪。</p> <p>复杂情绪，如悲伤、后悔和嫉妒，具有高度可变的表现形式和组成部分。</p> <p>基本情绪包括悲伤、愤怒、恐惧、厌恶、蔑视、快乐和惊讶，它们之所以被称为“基本”，是因为它们与普遍可识别的面部表情相关联。 例如，在厌恶的情绪中，你会看到上唇抬起、鼻梁皱起、面颊上扬。</p> <p>虽然基本情绪有时伴随着独特的面部表情和行为反应，但情绪和它们的表现之间并不存在一一对应关系。 以那些普遍可识别的面部表情为例。 非常有才华的演员可以模仿这些面部表情，而不产生相应的情绪。 相反，我们大多数人都擅长抑制伴随情绪的面部表情。 你可能真的感到悲伤，但在进入工作场所前露出大大的笑容，从而让同事误以为你很开心。</p> <p>即使我们的情绪表达反映了内心的精神生活，它们也未必是普遍可识别的。 这是因为基本情绪除了独特的面部表情、生理反应和行为倾向之外，还会引发许多其他的表现。 例子如下：</p> <ol> <li>强烈的悲伤可能导致的面部表情几乎无法与愤怒或暴怒区分开来。</li> <li>轻微的悲伤可能根本没有任何外在表现。</li> <li>当几种情绪同时存在时，其中一种情绪可能会占据主导地位，并在你的脸上表现出来。</li> <li>当情绪持续较长时间时，它们会在你的意识中进进出出。当你没有意识到它们时，情绪变得更难被察觉。</li> </ol> <p>基本情绪很可能自人类历史开端以来对我们的生存做出了重要贡献。 在这个意义上，“基本”（在“基本情绪”中的意思）只是指原始的（进化意义上的基本）。</p> <p>但如果一种情绪是真正的基本情绪，它怎么可能有更基本的成分呢？ 比如惊讶。 我们可以将惊讶分为两种反应：一种是积极的兴趣和好奇感，另一种是消极的恐慌感。 既然惊讶由其他情绪组成，为什么还称它为“基本”情绪呢？</p> <p>原因在于“基本”并不意味着“没有成分”。</p> <p>事实上，复杂情绪在不同人、不同情境和不同文化中有很大的差异。 虽然悲伤常被认为是惊讶、否认、悲伤和愤怒的混合体，但在某些人或文化中，悲伤可能完全不同。 例如，有些人在失去时从不表现出愤怒。其他人则通过愤怒来表达悲伤。</p> <p>悲伤常被认为由惊讶、否认、讨价还价、恐惧、愤怒、悲伤和接受组成。 这些成分通常不会在悲伤的过程中同时出现，而是会按顺序发生，并且不一定是我刚才列出的顺序。 虽然悲伤可能涉及这些构建块，但它可以通过许多其他方式表现出来。 如果损失是预料之中的，惊讶可能就不是成分之一。如果你为一位亲人的去世而悲伤，悲伤可能不涉及否认或讨价还价。 相反，如果你为一场分手而悲伤，你可能会经历长时间的否认分手的现实，并激烈地与前任讨价还价。 悲伤还可能伴随情绪的变化，包括抑郁、绝望、忧郁、易怒或焦虑的感觉，以及个性外在特征的临时改变，例如向孤立、不安全感、情绪化和警觉性转变。</p> <p>复杂情绪可能因为在人、情境和文化中的不同精神状态混合而成，所以它们不会引发普遍可识别的面部表情。</p> <p><strong>原文链接: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-superhuman-mind/201807/basic-and-complex-emotions">Basic and Complex Emotions</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>版权属于原作者，本翻译仅供学习用途。</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="repost"/><category term="phycology"/><category term="emotions"/><category term="CHN Available"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cultural variation and evolutionary advantages.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Are Basic Emotions?</title><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/what-are-basic-emotions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Are Basic Emotions?"/><published>2024-10-14T00:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T00:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/what-are-basic-emotions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/what-are-basic-emotions/"><![CDATA[<p>Neel Burton M.A., M.D. | Posted June 24, 2024 | Reviewed by Lybi Ma</p> <h2 id="key-points">Key Points</h2> <ul> <li>Basic emotions are innate and automatic, and trigger behaviour with a high survival value.</li> <li>They evolved in response to the ecological challenges faced by our remote ancestors.</li> <li>Although they are ‘hardwired’, their potential objects are open to cultural conditioning.</li> </ul> <p><a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/hide-and-seek/201601/what-are-basic-emotions?msockid=3cc8053b5a536d851b73102d5b446c8c"> <img src="https://cdn2.psychologytoday.com/assets/styles/article_inline_full_caption/public/field_blog_entry_images/2024-06/Plutchik-wheel.svg_.png.jpg?itok=W_OEkWEY" width="480" height="auto" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-1234"/> </a></p> <p>The concept of ‘basic’ or ‘primary’ emotions dates back at least to the Book of Rites, a first-century Chinese encyclopaedia that picks out seven ‘feelings of men’: joy, anger, sadness, fear, love, disliking, and liking.</p> <p>In the 20th century, Paul Ekman identified six basic emotions (anger, disgust, fear, happiness, sadness, and surprise) and Robert Plutchik eight, which he had in oppositional pairs (joy-sadness, anger-fear, trust-disgust, surprise-anticipation).</p> <p>Basic emotions are thought to have evolved in response to the ecological challenges faced by our remote ancestors and are so primitive as to be ‘hardwired’ into the brain, with each one operating along its own dedicated neurological circuit. Being hardwired, basic emotions (sometimes also called ‘affect programs’) are innate, automatic, and fast or reactive, and trigger behaviour with a high survival value.</p> <p>One day, while holidaying on the tropical island of Mauritius, I opened a cutlery drawer on a large lizard, which, of course, I had not been expecting to find in among the knives and forks. As the critter darted off into the darkness behind the drawer, I immediately and unthinkingly jumped back and slammed the drawer shut. Having done so, I suddenly became aware of feeling hot and alert and primed for further action. This basic fear response is so primitive that even the lizard seemed to share in it, and so automatic as to be ‘cognitively impenetrable’, that is, unconscious and uncontrollable, and more akin to a reflex or reaction than to a deliberate action. As soon as reason could reassert itself, my fear disappeared, leaving me with nothing more than a mildly inconvenient lizard problem, which, I think, I chose to ignore.</p> <p>One hypothesis is that basic emotions can function as building blocks, with more complex emotions being blends of basic ones. For instance, contempt might amount to a blend of anger and disgust. In 1980, Plutchik constructed a wheel-like diagram of emotions with eight basic emotions, plus eight derivative emotions each composed of two basic ones. However, many complex emotions cannot be deconstructed into more basic ones, and the theory does not explain why infants and animals do not share (or appear to share) in complex emotions.</p> <p>Instead, it could be that complex emotions are an amalgam of basic emotions and cognitions, with certain combinations being sufficiently common or important to be named in language. Thus, frustration might amount to anger combined with the thought or belief that ‘nothing can be done’. But again, many complex emotions resist such analysis. What’s more, ‘basic’ emotions can themselves result from quite complex cognitions, for instance, Tom’s blind panic upon realizing, or simply believing, that he has slept through an important exam.</p> <p>Although basic emotions have been compared to programmes, it does seem that their putative objects are open to cultural conditioning. If poor Tom so fears having missed his exam, this is in large part because of the value that his culture and sub-culture attach to academic success.</p> <p>With more complex emotions, it is the emotion itself (rather than its object) that is culturally shaped and constructed. Schadenfreude [German, lit. ‘harm-joy’: the joy or pleasure derived from the misfortune of another] is not common to all peoples in all times.</p> <p>Neither is romantic love, which seems to have emerged in tandem with the novel. In Madame Bovary, itself a novel, Gustave Flaubert tells us that Emma Bovary only found out about romantic love through “the refuse of old lending libraries.”</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Original Post: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/hide-and-seek/201601/what-are-basic-emotions?msockid=3cc8053b5a536d851b73102d5b446c8c">What Are Basic Emotions?</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>Copyright belongs to the original author.</em></strong></p> <hr style="border: 2px solid;"/> <h1 id="什么是基本情绪">什么是基本情绪？</h1> <p>Neel Burton M.A., M.D. | 2024年6月24日 | 审阅：Lybi Ma</p> <h2 id="重点">重点</h2> <ul> <li>基本情绪是天生且自动的，它们会引发具有高度生存价值的行为。</li> <li>它们是在远古祖先面临的生态挑战中进化而来的。</li> <li>尽管它们是“硬连接”的，但其潜在对象可以受到文化条件的影响。</li> </ul> <p>“基本”或“主要”情绪的概念至少可以追溯到《礼记》，这本一世纪的中国百科全书列出了人的七种”情感”：喜、怒、哀、惧、爱、恶、欲。</p> <blockquote> <p><strong>译者注：</strong>《礼记·礼运》：“何谓人情？喜、怒、哀、惧、爱、恶、欲，七者弗学而能。”</p> </blockquote> <p>在20世纪，保罗·艾克曼（Paul Ekman）确定了六种基本情绪（愤怒、厌恶、恐惧、快乐、悲伤和惊讶），而罗伯特·普鲁奇克（Robert Plutchik）则提出了八种基本情绪，并将它们成对对立（如快乐-悲伤，愤怒-恐惧，信任-厌恶，惊讶-期待）。</p> <p>人们认为基本情绪是在远古祖先面临的生态挑战中进化而来的，它们是如此原始，以至于“根植于”大脑中，每种情绪都沿着其专属的神经通路运作。 由于是固有的，基本情绪（有时也称为“情感程序”）是天生的、自动的、快速或反应性的，能够引发具有高度生存价值的行为。</p> <p>有一天，当我在毛里求斯的热带岛屿度假时，我打开了一个装餐具的抽屉，发现了一只大蜥蜴，当然，我没想到会在刀叉中找到它。 当那只蜥蜴飞快地逃进抽屉后面的黑暗中时，我立刻不假思索地跳了回来并猛地关上了抽屉。 做完这一切后，我突然意识到自己感到身体发热、警觉，并为进一步的行动做好了准备。 这种基本的恐惧反应是如此原始，以至于连蜥蜴似乎都能共享这种反应；它是如此自发，以至于是“认知上无法理解的”，即无意识且无法控制，更像是一种反射或反应，而非有意的行动。 一旦理智重新占上风，我的恐惧随即消失，只留下了一个有点不便的蜥蜴问题，我想，我选择了忽略它。</p> <p>一种假设认为，基本情绪可以作为构建模块，更多复杂的情绪是基本情绪的混合。 例如，蔑视可能是愤怒和厌恶的混合体。 1980年，普鲁奇克构建了一个类似轮子的情绪图，展示了八种基本情绪，以及由两种基本情绪组合而成的八种派生情绪。 然而，许多复杂的情绪无法被分解为更基本的情绪，且这一理论无法解释为什么婴儿和动物没有（或似乎没有）复杂情绪。</p> <p>相反，复杂情绪可能是基本情绪与认知的融合，某些组合在语言中足够普遍或重要，以至于被命名。 因此，沮丧可能是愤怒加上“无能为力”的想法或信念。 但是，许多复杂的情绪仍然无法通过这种方式进行分析。 此外，“基本”情绪本身可能源自相当复杂的认知，例如，汤姆意识到或仅仅认为，自己错过了重要考试时产生的盲目恐慌。</p> <p>尽管基本情绪常被比作程序，但似乎它们的假定对象可以受到文化条件的影响。 如果可怜的汤姆如此害怕错过考试，很大程度上是因为他的文化和亚文化对学术成功的重视。</p> <p>对于更复杂的情绪，情绪本身（而非它的对象）是由文化塑造和构建的。 例如，<em>Schadenfreude</em>（德语，意为“幸灾乐祸”：从他人不幸中获得的快乐或愉悦）并非所有时代所有民族共有的情感。</p> <p>浪漫爱情也不是，它似乎伴随着小说的出现而产生。 在小说《包法利夫人》中，居斯塔夫·福楼拜告诉我们，艾玛·包法利是通过“旧借书店的废物”才了解浪漫爱情的。</p> <hr/> <p><strong>原文链接: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/hide-and-seek/201601/what-are-basic-emotions?msockid=3cc8053b5a536d851b73102d5b446c8c">What Are Basic Emotions?</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>版权属于原作者，本翻译仅供学习用途。</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="repost"/><category term="phycology"/><category term="emotions"/><category term="CHN Available"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emotions such as fear and anger are hardwired.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">8 Sneaky Signs That Insecurity is Affecting Your Life and 5 Ways to Gain More Confidence</title><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/8-sneaky-signs-that-insecurity-is-affecting-your-life-and-5-ways-to-gain-more-confidence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="8 Sneaky Signs That Insecurity is Affecting Your Life and 5 Ways to Gain More Confidence"/><published>2024-10-13T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-13T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/8-sneaky-signs-that-insecurity-is-affecting-your-life-and-5-ways-to-gain-more-confidence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/8-sneaky-signs-that-insecurity-is-affecting-your-life-and-5-ways-to-gain-more-confidence/"><![CDATA[<p>Ashley Laderer, John Mutziger | 29 March 2022</p> <ul> <li>Insecurity is the feeling that you are inadequate or not good enough.</li> <li>You might be insecure if you are self-critical, a perfectionist, or someone who self-sabotages.</li> <li>You can become more confident through therapy and practicing having compassion for yourself.</li> <li>Visit Insider’s Health Reference library for more advice.</li> </ul> <p>It’s normal to feel mildly insecure from time to time, such as before a first date or an important job interview. However, if you find yourself feeling insecure most of the time, and if it’s getting in the way of you living your day-to-day life, you may have more deeply rooted insecurities that need to be addressed in order for you to live your life happily and to the fullest.</p> <p>Here are eight signs that you’re insecure, and five ways to become more secure.</p> <h2 id="1-you-feel-inadequate">1. You Feel Inadequate</h2> <p>One of the main signs of insecurity is feeling inadequate, or that you aren’t good enough, says Courtney Glickman, PhD, LMHC, therapist and owner of The Collective Healing Center. Glickman says this can stem from negative experiences like childhood neglect, bullying, critical partners, or even societal expectations. “These experiences of powerlessness and judgment shape how individuals view their own self-worth and competency and often perpetuate shame,” says Glickman.</p> <h2 id="2-youre-a-perfectionist">2. You’re a Perfectionist</h2> <p>People who are insecure may be perfectionists and strive for flawlessness in order to make them feel more secure, Glickman says. However, perfectionism leads to unhealthy levels of self-criticism and a need for control, causing you to feel constantly let down and burnt out, says Glickman.</p> <h2 id="3-you-feel-a-lot-of-envy-or-jealousy">3. You Feel a Lot of Envy or Jealousy</h2> <p>When you’re insecure and feel inadequate, you may feel threatened or in competition with others, leading to envy and jealousy, Glickman says. This is because rather than focusing on themselves, insecure people tend to focus on comparing themselves to others, which may result in negative emotions.</p> <h2 id="4-youre-harsh-and-critical-of-yourself">4. You’re Harsh and Critical of Yourself</h2> <p>Regardless if your insecurity stems from something that happened in childhood or you developed it as an adult, it can manifest in the form of harsh self-criticism, says Jennifer Chain, PhD, licensed psychologist and owner of Thrive for the People. You might motivate yourself with self-criticism, guilt, or punishment. “If you find yourself talking to yourself in harsh or even abusive ways, you may be tearing yourself down regularly and contributing to your insecurity,” says Chain.</p> <h2 id="5-you-shape-shift-depending-on-who-youre-with">5. You Shape-Shift Depending on Who You’re With</h2> <p>You may see yourself as a social chameleon, Chain says. For example, you might change your mannerisms, speech, likes, and dislikes depending on who you’re around, since you may not be sure of who you truly are, or if people will like and accept the real you. “You may juggle different personas depending on the context and the people around you. You may be very skilled at this kind of shape-shifting, but it is costly and exhausting to keep up,” says Chain.</p> <h2 id="6-you-fear-rejection-and-abandonment">6. You Fear Rejection and Abandonment</h2> <p>In relationships, you might fear that you will be rejected or abandoned. “You may be constantly on the lookout for signs that the relationship is not going well, that the other person is unhappy with you, or you are failing somehow,” says Chain. This can result in you taking everything personally, interpreting your partner’s behaviors or statements inaccurately, reacting irrationally, or anticipating worst-case scenarios, Chain says, which can derail a relationship because you may become overly demanding, critical, or needy, creating conflicts that weren’t really there in the first place.</p> <h2 id="7-you-self-sabotage">7. You Self-Sabotage</h2> <p>“As a result of the fear of rejection or abandonment, your insecurity may show up as self-sabotaging behaviors,” says Chain. This can range from sabotaging your own personal success or your relationships. Chain says some examples of this may be:</p> <ul> <li>Procrastinating on a project because you’re afraid of failing despite giving your best effort.</li> <li>Acting cold or distant towards a partner because you are not sure how they feel about you.</li> <li>Avoiding asking for a promotion at work because you don’t think you’re deserving enough.</li> <li>Turning to emotional eating or drinking because you don’t feel like you deserve to be cared for.</li> </ul> <h2 id="8-you-dont-let-people-see-your-messy-side">8. You Don’t Let People See Your “Messy” Side</h2> <p>Nobody’s perfect, and everyone has flaws and moments of weakness. However, if you’re very insecure you may refuse to let anybody see those parts of you. “You may have learned growing up that your love and worthiness depend on presenting a perfect, have-it-all-together, and extremely competent image of yourself,” says Chain. This can lead you to have a hard time being vulnerable and letting people see you make mistakes, feel helpless, or cry.</p> <h2 id="what-to-do-about-insecurity">What to Do About Insecurity</h2> <p>Squashing your insecurities and becoming more secure with who you are and your abilities won’t be easy, but with hard work over time it’s possible. Here are five tips to become more secure and gain confidence.</p> <h3 id="1-seek-therapy">1. Seek Therapy</h3> <p>One of the best things you can do for yourself is to talk to a licensed mental health professional who can help you gain insight into issues that cause your insecurity. “Through therapy, individuals can build skills to foster a stronger sense of self, improve relationships, and develop coping skills to manage symptoms,” says Glickman. Many different types of therapy can address insecurity and help you learn new skills, but dialectical behavior therapy (DBT) in particular is a type that Glickman recommends. “DBT is a wonderful approach that provides specific skills that focus on asking for what you want, saying no, and negotiating conflict without damaging the relationship,” says Glickman.</p> <h3 id="2-practice-self-compassion">2. Practice self-compassion</h3> <p>If you’re insecure, chances are you’re mentally beating yourself up often. Glickman suggests taking time to reflect and notice what you tend to judge and criticize about yourself. For example, is it your appearance, career, or relationships?</p> <p>The next time you notice you’re being overly self-critical, try switching up and speaking to yourself in a genuine, loving way, the same way you would to a close friend or family member. Remember to have compassion for yourself, as it’s been shown to help improve insecurity within relationships as well as overall mental health.</p> <h3 id="3-challenge-your-thoughts">3. Challenge your thoughts</h3> <p>A common component of therapy is learning to understand the connection between thoughts, feelings, and behaviors. Glickman says you can work to challenge the negative, irrational beliefs leading to your insecurity.</p> <p>“Question, challenge, and don’t believe everything you think. This allows you to cognitively restructure unhealthy thinking patterns,” says Glickman. Over time, you will learn to quickly identify unhealthy thoughts and move forward in a healthier way.</p> <h3 id="4-be-your-own-loving-parent">4. Be your own loving parent</h3> <p>If your insecurity stems from your upbringing, it can help to do some inner-child work. “Imagine you have a small child inside of you. How would you speak to and treat your little self with kindness and tenderness? Close your eyes and imagine telling that little child that they are safe with you. You will protect them and care for them, and you love them,” says Chain. This draws from attachment theory, which is the idea that we learned our relationship behaviors early on in life based on our upbringing. Chain says this tip can be especially helpful if you had an unsafe or unpredictable relationship with your caretakers. This is also an aspect of different types of therapy such as psychoanalysis, psychodynamic therapy, internal family systems, and emotionally focused therapy, says Chain.</p> <h3 id="5-aim-for-progress-over-perfection">5. Aim for progress over perfection</h3> <p>Strive for realistic, attainable goals, keeping in mind that true perfection does not exist. “Focus on progress, which allows for more recognition of accomplishments and ultimately improves productivity and motivation,” says Glickman. Celebrate wins, no matter how small, along the way.</p> <h3 id="insiders-takeaway">Insider’s takeaway</h3> <p>Insecurity can show up in a lot of ways, ranging from feeling inadequate to fearing rejection to self sabotaging. Regardless of the cause of your insecurity, putting in work through therapy and other strategies can help you become more secure.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Original Post: <a href="(https://www.businessinsider.nl/8-sneaky-signs-that-insecurity-is-affecting-your-life-and-5-ways-to-gain-more-confidence/)">8 Sneaky Signs That Insecurity is Affecting Your Life and 5 Ways to Gain More Confidence</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>Copyright belongs to the original author.</em></strong></p> <hr style="border: 2px solid;"/> <h1 id="不安全感悄然影响你生活的8个迹象以及增强自信的5种方法">不安全感悄然影响你生活的8个迹象，以及增强自信的5种方法</h1> <p>Ashley Laderer, John Mutziger | 2022年3月29日</p> <ul> <li>不安全感是指你感到自己不够好或不合格的一种感觉。</li> <li>如果你对自己过于苛刻，是个完美主义者，或者有自我破坏的倾向，你可能就有不安全感。</li> <li>通过治疗和练习自我同情，你可以变得更加自信。</li> <li>访问 Insider Health Reference library 以获取更多建议。</li> </ul> <p>偶尔感到轻微的不安全感是正常的，例如在第一次约会或重要的工作面试之前。 然而，如果你发现自己大多数时间都感到不安全，并且这种感觉阻碍了你的日常生活，你可能有更深层次的需要解决的不安全感，只有解决这些问题，你才能过上幸福和充实的生活。</p> <p>以下是你感到不安全的八个迹象，以及五种变得更有安全感的方法。</p> <h2 id="1-你感到不够好">1. 你感到不够好</h2> <p>不安全感的主要表现之一是感到自己不够好，或者不够优秀，治疗师兼The Collective Healing Center的所有者Courtney Glickman博士（LMHC）表示。 Glickman说，这可能源于一些消极的经历，如童年的忽视、霸凌、批评性的伴侣，甚至是社会期望。 “这些无力感和被评价的经历会塑造个体对自身价值和能力的看法，并常常导致羞耻感，”Glickman说道。</p> <h2 id="2-你是个完美主义者">2. 你是个完美主义者</h2> <p>不安全感的人可能是完美主义者，他们追求无缺陷的表现以让自己感到更有安全感，Glickman说。 然而，完美主义会导致不健康的自我批评和对控制的需求，使你感到不断失望和精疲力尽，Glickman指出。</p> <h2 id="3-你常感到嫉妒或羡慕">3. 你常感到嫉妒或羡慕</h2> <p>当你感到不安全并且觉得自己不够好时，你可能会觉得受到威胁，或与他人竞争，从而导致嫉妒和羡慕感，Glickman表示。 这是因为不安全感的人往往不专注于自己，而是将自己与他人比较，这可能会引发负面情绪。</p> <h2 id="4-你对自己非常苛刻">4. 你对自己非常苛刻</h2> <p>无论你的不安全感是来自童年经历，还是成年后发展出来的，它都可能以严厉的自我批评形式表现出来，持有执照的心理学家兼Thrive for the People的所有者Jennifer Chain博士指出。 你可能会通过自我批评、内疚或惩罚来激励自己。 “如果你发现自己对自己说话的方式过于苛刻甚至是虐待性的，你可能会经常贬低自己，进一步加剧你的不安全感，”Chain说道。</p> <h2 id="5-你会根据周围的人改变自己">5. 你会根据周围的人改变自己</h2> <p>你可能认为自己是个“社交变色龙”，Chain说。 例如，你可能会根据周围的人改变自己的行为、说话方式、喜好和厌恶，因为你不确定自己是谁，或者不确定别人是否会喜欢和接受真正的你。 “你可能会根据不同的情境和周围的人来扮演不同的角色。你可能非常擅长这种变换，但它会耗费大量精力并让你感到疲惫不堪，”Chain指出。</p> <h2 id="6-你害怕被拒绝和被抛弃">6. 你害怕被拒绝和被抛弃</h2> <p>在关系中，你可能害怕自己会被拒绝或被抛弃。 “你可能会时刻关注关系是否顺利，担心对方是否对你不满意，或者你是否在某些方面失败了，”Chain说。 这可能会导致你将一切都个人化，错误地解读伴侣的行为或言辞，做出非理性的反应，或预想最坏的情况，这会让一段关系偏离正轨，因为你可能会变得过于苛求、批评或依赖，从而制造原本不存在的冲突。</p> <h2 id="7-你会自我破坏">7. 你会自我破坏</h2> <p>“由于害怕被拒绝或被抛弃，你的不安全感可能会表现为自我破坏的行为，”Chain说。 这种行为可能包括破坏自己的个人成功或关系。 Chain举了一些例子：</p> <ul> <li>因为害怕尽全力后仍然失败，所以拖延一个项目。</li> <li>因为不确定对方的感受，所以对伴侣表现得冷漠或疏远。</li> <li>因为觉得自己不够格，所以不敢在工作中提出晋升要求。</li> <li>因为觉得自己不值得被照顾，所以会诉诸情感饮食或酗酒。</li> </ul> <h2 id="8-你不愿让别人看到自己混乱的一面">8. 你不愿让别人看到自己“混乱”的一面</h2> <p>没有人是完美的，每个人都有缺陷和软弱的时候。 然而，如果你非常不安全，你可能拒绝让任何人看到你的这些部分。 “你可能在成长过程中学到，爱与价值取决于你展现出的完美形象，即一切都在掌控之中且非常有能力，”Chain说道。 这可能会让你很难表现出脆弱的一面，或者让别人看到你犯错、感到无助或哭泣的样子。</p> <h2 id="如何应对不安全感">如何应对不安全感</h2> <p>消除不安全感并变得更加自信并不容易，但通过长期努力这是可以实现的。 以下是五个帮助你变得更有安全感并增强自信的建议。</p> <h3 id="1-寻求治疗">1. 寻求治疗</h3> <p>你可以为自己做的最好的一件事就是与持有执照的心理健康专家交谈，他们可以帮助你深入了解导致不安全感的问题。 “通过治疗，个体可以培养技能，建立更强的自我意识，改善人际关系，并学会应对症状的技能，”Glickman说道。 许多不同类型的治疗可以应对不安全感并帮助你学习新技能，Glickman特别推荐的是辩证行为治疗（DBT）。 “DBT是一种非常好的方法，它提供了具体的技巧，专注于如何提出需求、说‘不’以及在不破坏关系的情况下解决冲突，”Glickman说道。</p> <h3 id="2-练习自我关怀">2. 练习自我关怀</h3> <p>如果你不安全，可能你经常在心里责备自己。 Glickman建议花时间反思并注意你倾向于批评自己的方面。 例如，是你的外貌、职业还是人际关系？</p> <p>下一次你发现自己过度自我批评时，试着转换思路，用真诚、充满爱的方式与自己对话，就像你对待亲密的朋友或家人一样。 记住对自己要有同情心，因为研究表明，这有助于改善关系中的不安全感，以及整体心理健康。</p> <h3 id="3-挑战你的想法">3. 挑战你的想法</h3> <p>治疗的一个常见组成部分是学习理解思想、情感和行为之间的联系。 Glickman表示，你可以努力挑战导致不安全感的消极、非理性信念。</p> <p>“质疑、挑战，不要相信你想的每一件事。这可以帮助你在认知上重建不健康的思维模式，”Glickman说。 随着时间的推移，你会学会快速识别不健康的想法，并以更健康的方式前进。</p> <h3 id="4-成为你自己的爱心父母">4. 成为你自己的爱心父母</h3> <p>如果你的不安全感源自童年经历，做一些内在小孩的工作会有帮助。 “想象你内心有一个小孩。你会如何用善意和温柔对待这个小孩？闭上眼睛，想象告诉那个小孩，他们和你在一起是安全的。你会保护他们，照顾他们，并且你爱他们，”Chain说。 这源自依恋理论，即我们早期的养育方式塑造了我们在成年后的关系行为。 Chain表示，如果你在童年时期与照顾者的关系不安全或不可预测，这一方法会尤其有帮助。 这也是许多不同治疗方法的组成部分，如精神分析、心理动力治疗、内在家庭系统治疗和情感聚焦治疗，Chain指出。</p> <h3 id="5-追求进步而非完美">5. 追求进步，而非完美</h3> <p>努力追求现实的、可达到的目标，牢记真正的完美并不存在。 “专注于进步，这能让你更容易意识到自己的成就，并最终提高生产力和动力，”Glickman说道。 无论多么小的胜利都要庆祝。</p> <h2 id="insider的结论">Insider的结论</h2> <p>不安全感可能以多种方式表现出来，从感到自己不够好，到害怕被拒绝，再到自我破坏。 无论是什么导致了你的不安全感，通过治疗和其他策略的努力工作，可以帮助你变得更加自信。</p> <hr/> <p><strong>原文链接: <a href="(https://www.businessinsider.nl/8-sneaky-signs-that-insecurity-is-affecting-your-life-and-5-ways-to-gain-more-confidence/)">8 Sneaky Signs That Insecurity is Affecting Your Life and 5 Ways to Gain More Confidence</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>版权属于原作者，本翻译仅供学习用途。</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="repost"/><category term="phycology"/><category term="insecurity"/><category term="CHN Available"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ashley Laderer, John Mutziger | 29 March 2022]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The 3 Most Common Causes of Insecurity and How to Beat Them</title><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/the-3-most-ommon-causes-of-insecurity-and-how-to-beat-them/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 3 Most Common Causes of Insecurity and How to Beat Them"/><published>2024-10-12T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/the-3-most-ommon-causes-of-insecurity-and-how-to-beat-them</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/the-3-most-ommon-causes-of-insecurity-and-how-to-beat-them/"><![CDATA[<p>Melanie Greenberg Ph.D. | Posted December 6, 2015 | Reviewed by Lybi Ma</p> <h2 id="key-points">Key Points</h2> <ul> <li>Insecurity can be based on recent failures: Research shows up to 40% of one’s “happiness quotient” is based on recent life events.</li> <li>Social anxiety from being bullied or having critical parents can lead to insecurity.</li> <li>Perfectionism can cause insecurity, depression, anxiety, eating disorders, and chronic fatigue.</li> </ul> <p>Do you find yourself filled with self-doubt and short on confidence? Despite your accomplishments, do you feel like a fraud destined to be exposed? Do you feel that you don’t deserve lasting love and that partners will inevitably leave you? Do you stay at home, afraid to venture out and meet new people because you don’t feel you have enough to offer? Do you feel overweight, boring, stupid, guilty, or ugly?</p> <p>Most of us feel insecure sometimes, but some of us feel insecure most of the time. The kind of childhood you had, past traumas, recent experiences of failure or rejection, loneliness, social anxiety, negative beliefs about yourself, perfectionism, or having a critical parent or partner can all contribute to insecurity.</p> <p>Following are the three most common forms of insecurity—and how to begin to cope with them.</p> <h2 id="type-1-insecurity-based-on-recent-failure-or-rejection">Type 1: Insecurity Based on Recent Failure or Rejection</h2> <p>Recent events can greatly affect both our mood and the way we feel about ourselves. Research on happiness suggests up to 40% of our “happiness quotient” is based on recent life events. The biggest negative contributor to happiness is the ending of a relationship, followed by the death of a spouse, job loss, and negative health events. Since unhappiness also influences your self-esteem, failure and rejection can deliver a double whammy to your confidence.</p> <p><strong>Below are some tools to overcome failure- or rejection-based insecurity:</strong></p> <ol> <li>Give yourself time to heal and adapt to the new normal.</li> <li>Get out and engage with life, following your interests and curiosity.</li> <li>Reach out to friends and family for distraction and comfort.</li> <li>Get feedback from people you trust.</li> <li>Persevere and keep moving towards your goals.</li> <li>Be willing to try a different strategy if necessary.</li> </ol> <h2 id="type-2-lack-of-confidence-because-of-social-anxiety">Type 2: Lack of Confidence Because of Social Anxiety</h2> <p>Many of us experience a lack of confidence in social situations like parties, family gatherings, interviews, and dates. The fear of being evaluated by others—and found to be lacking—can lead to feeling anxious and self-conscious. This type of insecurity is generally based on distorted beliefs about your self-worth and the extent to which others are evaluating you.</p> <p><strong>Below are some tools to combat insecurity in social situations:</strong></p> <ol> <li>Talk back to your inner critic. Remind yourself of all the reasons you can be interesting and fun or a good friend or partner.</li> <li>Prepare in advance. Think of things you can talk about—current events, movies, hobbies, your job, or your family.</li> <li>Avoiding social situations just makes things worse. So go to a party or on a date even if you’re nervous.</li> <li>Set yourself a limited, realistic goal. This could be anything from talking to two new people or finding out more about one person’s work and hobbies.</li> <li>Deliberately focus on others to combat intense self-focus. Put on your observer hat and notice what other people seem to be feeling and doing.</li> </ol> <h2 id="type-3-insecurity-driven-by-perfectionism">Type 3: Insecurity Driven by Perfectionism</h2> <p>Some of us have very high standards for everything we do. Life doesn’t always turn out exactly the way we want, even if we work extra hard. There is a piece of the outcome that is at least partly out of our control. If you are constantly disappointed and blaming yourself for being anything less than perfect, you will start to feel insecure and unworthy.</p> <p><strong>Below are some ways to combat perfectionism:</strong></p> <ol> <li>Evaluate yourself based on effort rather than outcome, which can be dependent on external factors.</li> <li>Think about how much difference it would actually make if your work were 10% better.</li> <li>Find the grey areas in all-or-nothing thinking. Is there a more compassionate way to view a situation?</li> <li>Focus on inner qualities like your character, sincerity, or good values, rather than just on external achievements.</li> </ol> <hr/> <p><strong>Original Post: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/gb/blog/the-mindful-self-express/201512/the-3-most-common-causes-of-insecurity-and-how-to-beat-them">The 3 Most Common Causes of Insecurity and How to Beat Them</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>Copyright belongs to the original author.</em></strong></p> <hr style="border: 2px solid;"/> <h1 id="三种最常见的不安全感及其应对方法">三种最常见的不安全感及其应对方法</h1> <p>Melanie Greenberg Ph.D. | 2015年12月6日 | 审阅：Lybi Ma</p> <h2 id="重点">重点</h2> <ul> <li>不安全感可能源于最近的失败：研究显示，40%的“幸福指数”基于最近的生活事件。</li> <li>由于被欺负或有批评性父母而产生的社交焦虑可能导致不安全感。</li> <li>完美主义不仅会导致不安全感，还会引起抑郁、焦虑、饮食失调和慢性疲劳。</li> </ul> <p>你是否觉得自己充满了自我怀疑并缺乏自信？ 尽管取得了成就，但你是否觉得自己像一个将被揭穿的骗子？ 你是否觉得自己不配拥有持久的爱，伴侣最终都会离开你？你是否因为觉得自己没有足够的价值而待在家里，害怕走出去认识新朋友？ 你是否觉得自己超重、无聊、愚蠢、有罪或丑陋？</p> <p>我们大多数人有时会感到不安全，但有些人几乎总是感到不安全。 你的童年经历、过去的创伤、最近的失败或拒绝经历、孤独、社交焦虑、对自己的负面信念、完美主义或有批评性的父母或伴侣都可能导致不安全感。</p> <p>以下是三种最常见的不安全感形式以及如何开始应对它们的方法。</p> <h2 id="类型1基于最近失败或拒绝的不安全感">类型1：基于最近失败或拒绝的不安全感</h2> <p>最近的事件可以极大地影响我们的情绪和自我感觉。 关于幸福的研究表明，40%的“幸福指数”基于最近的生活事件。 最大的不幸福来源是关系的结束，其次是配偶的死亡、失业和健康事件的不良变化。 由于不幸福也会影响你的自尊，失败和拒绝会对你的自信心造成双重打击。</p> <p><strong>以下是一些克服基于失败或拒绝的不安全感的工具：</strong></p> <ol> <li>给自己时间愈合并适应新的常态。</li> <li>走出去，按照你的兴趣和好奇心积极投入生活。</li> <li>向朋友和家人寻求分散注意力和安慰。</li> <li>从你信任的人那里获得反馈。</li> <li>坚持下去，继续朝着你的目标前进。</li> <li>如果需要，愿意尝试不同的策略。</li> </ol> <h2 id="类型2由于社交焦虑导致的缺乏自信">类型2：由于社交焦虑导致的缺乏自信</h2> <p>我们中的许多人在社交场合（如聚会、家庭聚会、面试和约会）中会缺乏自信。 害怕被他人评估并被发现不足会让你感到焦虑和难为情。 这种不安全感通常基于对自我价值的扭曲信念以及对他人评估你的程度的错误认知。</p> <p><strong>以下是一些应对社交情境中不安全感的工具：</strong></p> <ol> <li>反击你的内心批评家。提醒自己所有让你变得有趣和愉快或成为好朋友或伴侣的原因。</li> <li>提前准备。想一些你可以谈论的话题——当前事件、你看过的电影、爱好、工作或家庭。</li> <li>避免社交情境只会使情况更糟。所以即使紧张也要去参加聚会或约会。</li> <li>给自己设定一个有限的、现实的目标。这可以是与两个人谈话或了解一个人的工作和爱好。</li> <li>故意关注他人以对抗强烈的自我关注。戴上观察者的帽子，注意其他人似乎在感受和做什么。</li> </ol> <h2 id="类型3由完美主义驱动的不安全感">类型3：由完美主义驱动的不安全感</h2> <p>我们中有些人对自己所做的一切都有很高的标准。 即使我们加倍努力，生活也不总是按我们的意愿进行。 结果的一部分至少在某种程度上超出了我们的控制范围。 如果你总是感到失望并责怪自己不够完美，你会开始感到不安全和不配得。</p> <p><strong>以下是一些应对完美主义的方法：</strong></p> <ol> <li>试着根据你投入的努力而不是结果来评价自己，因为结果往往取决于外部因素。</li> <li>想一想你的工作如果提高10%会有多大差别。检查和重新检查或回复每封电子邮件所花的时间和精力是否真的值得？</li> <li>完美主义通常基于非黑即白的思维方式，所以试着找到灰色地带。是否有更有同情心的或理解的方式来看待情况？</li> <li>关注内在的品质，如你的性格、真诚或良好的价值观，而不仅仅是外部的成就。</li> </ol> <hr/> <p><strong>原文链接: <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/gb/blog/the-mindful-self-express/201512/the-3-most-common-causes-of-insecurity-and-how-to-beat-them">The 3 Most Common Causes of Insecurity and How to Beat Them</a></strong></p> <p><strong><em>版权属于原作者，本翻译仅供学习用途。</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="repost"/><category term="phycology"/><category term="insecurity"/><category term="CHN Available"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[15 tools to help you bounce back when you're feeling down about yourself.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tips for Writing a Power Engineering Paper</title><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/tips-for-writing-a-power-engineering-paper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tips for Writing a Power Engineering Paper"/><published>2024-09-29T14:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-29T14:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/tips-for-writing-a-power-engineering-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/tips-for-writing-a-power-engineering-paper/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="writing-is-to-know-yourself">Writing is to know yourself</h1> <p>Articulating your ideas helps know your own opinions, even if you have many vibrant thoughts before writing. As a result, it would be a little bit challenging to write down something without carefully thinking it.</p> <p>Some students might already have the capability of critical thinking before graduate school, but some might need to develop the skill when they are asked to write a formal article. For the second group, the first article can be a little bit painful, but no worry, it will be better and better.</p> <h1 id="balance-the-key-message-and-the-presentation-quality">Balance the key message and the presentation quality</h1> <p>Regarding the engineering papers, I would say people expect to learn something new from it. Otherwise, the article might be considered more of performance art, as it mainly shows the author’s superiority of intelligence or writing.</p> <p>Before writing, it is important to clarify what is the key message you want to deliver to the audience. Although people can have diverse opinions on what is interesting, convincing at least a few people is a good start.</p> <p>Once you determine the key message, you can start to write. However, the key message can change during the paper development, and it is okay to adjust the message as long as you feel it is exciting. The following book gives a good guide on how to write a paper in engineering:</p> <p><strong>H. B. Michaelson</strong>, <em>How to Write and Publish Engineering Papers and Reports</em>, 3rd edition, Westport, CT: Greenwood Press, 1990.</p> <h1 id="common-mistakes-in-writing-ieee-papers">Common mistakes in writing IEEE papers:</h1> <p>There is a summary of the common mistakes in writing IEEE papers by <a href="https://web.eecs.utk.edu/~tolbert/">Dr. Leon Tolbert</a>. The summary is informative and thus excerpted here for power engineering students.</p> <div> <ol> <li> Follow IEEE formatting for references: <br/> <div style="text-align: left;"> <img src="/assets/img/poster/IEEE_bib_format.png" alt="IEEE" style="width: 400px; height: auto;"/> </div> </li> <br/> <li> Format figures as follows. In the main text, it should read, “… as shown in Fig. 1.”<br/> <br/> Or, another example, “as seen by the waveform in Fig. 2(a), the voltage has significant harmonic content.”<br/> <br/> Figure captions should be formatted as follows:<br/> Fig. 1. Voltage waveform for the output of the dc-dc converter. </li> <br/> <li> After an equation, where you want to list what some of the variables are, the word “where” should be lowercase and at the left margin (not indented). Microsoft Word incorrectly will indent and capitalize. </li> <br/> <li> References should be inside [ ] and should be inside the period at the end of the sentence:<br/> <br/> Examples: “… and hence the amount of shunt compensation in the power system can be controlled [2].”<br/> <br/> “… with small effects on the dc link voltage [7, 9-11].”<br/> <br/> “Reference [8] provides information on how the …”<br/> </li> <br/> <li> Equations should be numbered in parentheses () and mentioned by number only without saying “Equation” or “Eq.” except at the beginning of a sentence:<br/> <br/> “… by substituting (3) into (1), the following expression is obtained.”<br/> <br/> “Equation (8) shows that torque is directly proportional to …”<br/> </li> <br/> <li> The unit should be abbreviated and follow the number separated by a space:<br/> <br/> Examples: 10 kW, 1200 V, 5.5 mA, 10 MHz, 300 °C, 20 s, 75 kHz.<br/> Wrong: 100W, 300C, 50 KHZ, 60 sec.<br/> </li> <br/> <li> Italicize symbols when used in the text:<br/> <br/> “… With reference to wind speed <i>v</i>, wind turbine radius <i>r</i>, turbine rotational speed <i>ω</i>, turbine sweeping area <i>A</i>, and air density <i>ρ</i>.” </li> <br/> <li> Do not use contractions in the paper (don’t, can’t, it’s, etc.). Instead, write out the words (do not, cannot, it is). </li> <br/> <li> Spell out abbreviations for the first time: “hybrid electric vehicles (HEVs), pulse width modulation (PWM), insulated gate bipolar transistor (IGBT)” </li> <br/> <li> Use a comma after introductory phrases: “With the increased use of non-linear loads on the utility, better metering and compensation techniques are needed...”<br/> <br/> "Before researching any new ideas on a subject, it is useful to look at current standards in the area."<br/> <br/> "For a single phase active filter using a voltage source inverter and coupling inductor, the limit cycle parameter after linearization are given by (24-25)." </li> <br/> <li> For a list of 3 or more items, separate by commas including before the word “and”.<br/> <br/> Example: “SiC devices have lower on-resistance, higher blocking voltages, and higher thermal endurance.” </li> <br/> <li> For a compound sentence (subject - verb, and subject - verb), separate by a comma.<br/> <br/> Example: “The IGBT and diode are soldered directly to the collector plate, and solder is used on each side of the spacers.”<br/> <br/> "Its function is limited, but its cost is low since it just makes a small improvement on the existing distribution transformers in the grid." </li> <br/> <li> Avoid using the following words (these are a little too simple and vague): <ol type="a"> <li>big</li> <li>got</li> <li>good</li> <li>bad</li> <li>problem</li> <li>“a lot” - use “several” or “many” instead</li> </ol> </li> <br/> <li> “Analysis” is a noun; “analyze” is a verb. </li> <br/> <li> Write papers in the third person. Do not use “you”, “we”, “us”, “our”. </li> <br/> <li> Do not use the words “firstly”, “secondly”, etc. Use “first”, “second”. </li> <br/> <li> Do not use the word “Besides…” to start a sentence. Instead, use “In addition…” or “Also…”. </li> <br/> <li> “Unbalanced” is preferred over “imbalance”. </li> <br/> <li> Capitalize the headings in papers, e.g., “A. Basic Converter Control” instead of “A. basic converter control”. </li> <br/> <li> Be specific in figure captions. It should say, “Fig. 10. MPPT control strategy for cascaded H-bridge multilevel converters used in wind generators.” and not “Fig. 10. Control strategy.” </li> <br/> <li> Be sure figures are fully labeled with units and identify what each waveform represents. </li> <br/> <li> Keep paragraphs short - about 4 to 5 sentences each; it makes the paper much more readable. </li> <br/> </ol> </div> <p>Note that some of the above rules are specific to IEEE papers and might not be applicable to other disciplines.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="writing"/><category term="research"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing is to know yourself]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Art and Science, The Difference Between Expression and Core</title><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/art-and-science-the-difference-between-expression-and-core/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Art and Science, The Difference Between Expression and Core"/><published>2024-09-17T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-17T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/art-and-science-the-difference-between-expression-and-core</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/art-and-science-the-difference-between-expression-and-core/"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left;"> <img src="/assets/img/poster/Moky.png" alt="Moky" style="width: 350px; height: auto;"/> <p><em>Moky in 2022</em></p> </div> <p>In the realms of art and science, the relationship between expression and core content shows significant differences. This perspective came to me during an English course, and recently, after a peculiar dream, I thought of an argument supporting this viewpoint.</p> <p>For art, even if the core idea remains the same, using different forms of expression can be considered innovative. Art carries human subjective emotions, and different forms of expression can trigger different emotional experiences.</p> <p>For example: Painting: The same theme can be expressed through oil painting, watercolor, sketching, etc., each bringing different visual effects and emotional resonance. Music: A pop song’s studio version, live concert version, and versions remade with different instrumental effects all provide different auditory experiences and emotional reactions. This diversity and innovation allow art to continually bring new feelings and inspirations to people.</p> <p>In contrast, science explores objective laws, and as long as the core idea is the same, it does not bring new knowledge. Scientific discoveries emphasize substance rather than form of expression. Here are some reasons:</p> <ul> <li>Objectivity of Science: Scientific discoveries need to convey information accurately, avoiding misunderstandings or ambiguities. Different forms of expression might lead to distortion or misunderstanding of information.</li> <li>Verification and Reproducibility: Scientific discoveries need to be verified and replicated to confirm their reliability. Different forms of expression might affect the reproducibility and verification process.</li> <li>Professional Audience: The audience for scientific discoveries is usually professionals who focus more on the substantive content and data rather than the form of expression.</li> </ul> <p>In summary, art and science show significant differences in the relationship between expression and core content. The diversity and innovation in art lie in its changing forms of expression, while the rigor and objectivity in science lie in its stable core content. Understanding this helps us better appreciate the unique charm of both art and scientific discoveries.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="culture"/><category term="opinion"/><category term="art"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moky in 2022]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Is The Boundary Between Science and Engineering?</title><link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/what-is-the-boundary-between-science-and-engineering/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Is The Boundary Between Science and Engineering?"/><published>2024-06-30T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-30T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/what-is-the-boundary-between-science-and-engineering</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jinningwang.github.io/blog/2024/what-is-the-boundary-between-science-and-engineering/"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left;"> <img src="/assets/img/poster/alpaca.png" alt="An alpaca in the Safari Park by Buxin She" style="width: 550px; height: auto;"/> <p><em>An alpaca in the Safari Park by Buxin She</em></p> </div> <p>As a Ph.D. student in the electrical engineering (to be more specific, power systems), I’ve been thinking the question posed in the headline recently. I’d like to share my thoughts about it.</p> <p>It arises from the research experience these years. Sometimes, after an idea is brought up, there might be a question “what’s new?” or “what’s the novelty?” It can occur in a paper review or a project meeting.</p> <p>I feel the motivation for novelty or something new, can be traced back to curiosity. Like the questions “why can fireflies light up”, or “why can the fireflies in Smoky Mountain synchronize?” When the answers to such questions are not directly relevant to practical concerns like paying rent, they can be regarded as <strong><em>Science</em></strong>, and they can bring joy. Conversely, if the answers can save people from tedious repetitive work, I would call it <strong><em>Engineering</em></strong>. Now, my answer to the question in headline is engineering is expected to make life better in a short period of time, while science is not expected to have immediate and direct implications on daily life. However, “novelty” itself is <strong>NOT BOUNDED</strong> to engineering or science.</p> <p>Here are some interesting answers I received recently:</p> <ul> <li>“Science is about the nature of the world, like the Newton’s laws of motion, or Maxwell’s equations. Engineering is about man-made things.”</li> <li>“Science is about why, and engineering is about how.”</li> <li>“Where science stops, engineering start.”</li> </ul> <p>Lastly, there’s a blog by Michael J. Black about the review process that I found interesting: <a href="https://perceiving-systems.blog/en/news/novelty-in-science">Novelty in Science</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="culture"/><category term="opinion"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An alpaca in the Safari Park by Buxin She]]></summary></entry></feed>